<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Patents on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/tags/patents/</link><description>Recent content in Patents on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 10:12:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.com/tags/patents/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spent more on Patents than R&amp;D?</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/10/10/spent-more-on-patents-than-r/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 10:12:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/10/10/spent-more-on-patents-than-r/</guid><description>Ian Betteridge @ianbetteridge takes the New York Times down in Did Apple and Google really spend more on patents than R&amp;amp;D?, in response to the NYT article The iEconomy: Apple and Technology Manufacturing (Subscription required):
Read the NYT piece, and you would think that the technology market has shifted from being about research and development of new products to being about acquisition of patents. Given that this is based on a single year, when some very big patent portfolios came on the market in one-off deals that aren’t likely to be repeated in the future, that’s a long way from the truth.</description></item><item><title>Thwarted by Patents</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/08/25/thwarted-by-patents/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 11:33:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/08/25/thwarted-by-patents/</guid><description>As you all know, teleportation is easy. But one cannot make a teleporter due to the crazy US Patent system. And it&amp;rsquo;s frustrating me.
Like you all, I am pretty tired of traveling to airports via trains and monorails, waiting in check-in lines, fighting those darn kiosk things, standing in baggage lines, standing in TSA lines, removing shoes and belt, getting frisked, getting dressed then waiting in dingy boarding areas with horrid coffee and no useable wifi only to spend hours upon hours squished in small cramped seats with bland food and annoying strangers, just to get somewhere.</description></item><item><title>Why patents are a big problem</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/01/11/why-patents-are-a-big-problem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 09:39:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/01/11/why-patents-are-a-big-problem/</guid><description>Brad Lindenberg nails it in Why patents are a big f******* problem
There has to be a correlation between ideas and execution otherwise those who can execute get shafted by those who cannot.
I don&amp;rsquo;t have a problem with patenting a physical thing that you make, I do have a problem patenting an idea, concept or discovery.</description></item></channel></rss>