<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Octopress on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/tags/octopress/</link><description>Recent content in Octopress on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 16:28:04 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.com/tags/octopress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Upgrading Octopress to Jekyll 2.0</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2014/06/21/upgrading-octopress-to-jekyll-2-dot-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 16:28:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2014/06/21/upgrading-octopress-to-jekyll-2-dot-0/</guid><description>So this happened today:
Octopress 2 is now using the latest and greatest Jekyll 2.0.3.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Now, back to work on Octopress 3. Happy blogging!
&amp;mdash; Octopress (@octopress) June 21, 2014 I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for this. Now that it has, I decided to finally upgrade this site.
It was easy. As per Updating Octopress, I just ran:
git pull octopress master Then, to ensure all gems were up to date, I ran</description></item><item><title>Octopress now has Footnotes</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/08/octopress-now-has-footnotes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 17:30:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/08/octopress-now-has-footnotes/</guid><description>If you update to the latest Octopress and you still use the rdiscount markdown processor, you now get footnotes like this 1. I was previously using a CSS workaround because I prefer the speed of rdiscount for my growing site2 and still wanted footnotes.
To create a footnote, use the standard MultiMarkdown [^1] anchor to create the footnote reference link, and add [^1]: The footnote content. to the bottom of the file3.</description></item><item><title>18 Months of Octopress</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/17/18-months-of-octopress/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 13:23:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/17/18-months-of-octopress/</guid><description>A lot of reviews are written by people who played with the product for a few hours and report their first impressions. This is all about a product I have been using for 18 months every day: Octopress, the blogging platform behind hiltmon.com.
Before Octopress I consolidated to hiltmon.com from a series of sites based on Wordpress and a static site generated by RapidWeaver.
The Wordpress sites drove me crazy. Wordpress itself was (and still is) buggy, inexplicably complicated and slow to render.</description></item><item><title>Add Web Clip Icons to Octopress</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/10/add-web-clip-icons-to-octopress/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 13:57:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/10/add-web-clip-icons-to-octopress/</guid><description>The default Octopress setup includes a favicon.png which enables you to place your own tiny icon to the left of the URL in most browsers. You should see a small blue cog there now.
Both Apple and Android phones also support saving a link to a site (called a web clip) on your phone as an icon. Over the past few days, it seems quite a few viewers of this site have added it as a web clip, but I had not provided good iconage.</description></item><item><title>New Site Font</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/08/05/new-site-font/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2012 15:33:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/08/05/new-site-font/</guid><description>I love Octopress, but I have never been happy with the default fonts. The default PT Sans and PT Serif fonts are very, very nice, but not awesome. I did like the X and Y height, the clarity, the ease of reading, but the letterspacing on the serif font was too tight and it started to look jaggy.
This week, Adobe released Source Sans Pro, their first free and open font, and I think it’s great for a technical blog-style web site.</description></item><item><title>Octopress Post and Publish</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/07/18/octopress-post-and-publish/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 18:01:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/07/18/octopress-post-and-publish/</guid><description>Since this site is getting larger and it&amp;rsquo;s running on Octopress, the rake generate and rake preview processes are getting slower. Enter rake isolate[&amp;quot;x&amp;quot;] to isolate the site down to the selected post. But isolating requires me to note the file name down, there is too much to remember and type and I am lazy.
So have created two macros and a script to speed this process up.
Note: You must run these commands in the root of the Octopress folder, else they will not work at all!</description></item><item><title>Application Context Packs</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/04/26/application-context-packs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 09:49:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/04/26/application-context-packs/</guid><description>When developing in Rails, I use a certain pack of applications; when coding for iOS, I use a different pack of applications; and when in a blogging context, I use a third pack of applications. And then there is the regular set of applications that I usually leave running. Starting and switching between these contexts used to take time, until I found a better way.
The Old Way
After a clean reboot, I would then have to go through the same dance every time, launch the regular applications manually.</description></item><item><title>My Blog Writing Workflow</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/03/15/my-blog-writing-workflow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2012 14:52:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/03/15/my-blog-writing-workflow/</guid><description>With the release of Byword for iOS (iTunes app store link), my blog writing workflow has come full circle.
All posts start as ideas and notes jotted down in nvAlt, Brett Terpstra&amp;rsquo;s fork of Notational Velocity. I like this product because the search and use of notes is fully integrated, and it supports markdown. I have set it up so that all notes are stored as markdown files in a Dropbox folder and Byword has been set up as the external editor.</description></item><item><title>Thank you for a great February</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/03/01/thank-you-for-a-great-february/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 11:13:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/03/01/thank-you-for-a-great-february/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been two months since I consolidated all my sites into this blog and started writing more. This blog just has a great February and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share some stats.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>All to Octopress</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/02/16/all-to-octopress/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 19:51:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/02/16/all-to-octopress/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have moved all of my sites over to &lt;a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="http://brandonmathis.com/">Brandin Mathis&lt;/a>. This means &lt;a href="https://hiltmon.com">hiltmon.com&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.noverse.com">noverse.com&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.shukaico.com">shukaico.com&lt;/a> are all on the same platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Migrating to Octopress</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/11/22/migrating-to-octopress/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 20:10:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/11/22/migrating-to-octopress/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over the years I have created a series of blogs, but never found my voice. It&amp;rsquo;s time to do it better. So here it is, my voice, my errors, my opinions, my mistakes, my soapbox, and maybe, just maybe, someday I&amp;rsquo;ll write something interesting, &lt;em>in my voice&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>