<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Status Board on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/tags/status-board/</link><description>Recent content in Status Board on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 19:47:54 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.com/tags/status-board/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New Google Analytics for Status Board Server Edition</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2015/06/07/new-google-analytics-for-status-board-server-edition/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 19:47:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2015/06/07/new-google-analytics-for-status-board-server-edition/</guid><description>Last week, Google finally deprecated their non-Oauth APIs, which means that the Google Analytics for Status Board code I have been publishing stopped working. Fortunately for us, Github user erebusnz updated the PHP API to work with OAuth2 and we can access Google again. I have included it in a new version of the Server Edition Package.
Quick Install Instructions Download the statusboard.zip file. Expand it in the root of your web server.</description></item><item><title>Google Analytics for Status Board Server Edition</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/30/google-analytics-for-status-board-server-edition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 16:59:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/30/google-analytics-for-status-board-server-edition/</guid><description>Google has finally deprecated their GAPI interface which this used to talk to Google Analytics, sorry folks, it will no longer work. See the New Google Analytics for Status Board Server Edition for an updated version. Dropbox went down today, and I found out when my Status Board stopped updating. This spurred me on to migrate my Google Analytics for Status Board scripts from Ruby and Dropbox over to server based PHP.</description></item><item><title>Add GA OS and Browser to Status Board</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/17/add-ga-os-and-browser-to-status-board/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 11:02:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/17/add-ga-os-and-browser-to-status-board/</guid><description>Google has finally deprecated their GAPI interface which this used to talk to Google Analytics, sorry folks, it will no longer work. See the New Google Analytics for Status Board Server Edition for an updated version. Reader Brandon Cozart (@brandoncozart) asked if it were possible to add Browser and OS statistics to the Google Analytics for Status Board scripts. So I gave it a shot.
Update: Download again if you use these scripts, a null value bug and sorting bugs have been fixed.</description></item><item><title>Hourly Analytics for Status Board</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/15/hourly-analytics-for-status-board/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 10:23:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/15/hourly-analytics-for-status-board/</guid><description>Google has finally deprecated their GAPI interface which this used to talk to Google Analytics, sorry folks, it will no longer work. See the New Google Analytics for Status Board Server Edition for an updated version. Following up last week&amp;rsquo;s Google Analytics for Status Board graph and Top Pages table on Status Board, a reader asked for hourly stats instead of daily, so I created it (see the bottom-right graph).</description></item><item><title>Top Pages in Status Board</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/10/top-pages-in-status-board/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 16:06:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/10/top-pages-in-status-board/</guid><description>Google has finally deprecated their GAPI interface which this used to talk to Google Analytics, sorry folks, it will no longer work. See the New Google Analytics for Status Board Server Edition for an updated version. Following up this morning&amp;rsquo;s Google Analytics for Status Board graph on Status Board, I also wanted a top pages for today view for Hiltmon.com.
See also Hourly Stats and OS and Browser Stats.
The steps are all the same as Google Analytics for Status Board, so follow along, only replace those script and the launcher files with these.</description></item><item><title>Google Analytics for Status Board</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/10/google-analytics-for-status-board/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 12:15:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/10/google-analytics-for-status-board/</guid><description>Google has finally deprecated their GAPI interface which this used to talk to Google Analytics, sorry folks, it will no longer work. See the New Google Analytics for Status Board Server Edition for an updated version. I wanted to see the 7-day Hiltmon.com web stats from Google Analytics on Panic&amp;rsquo;s new Status Board app. Here is how I got it to work.
Update: For a far simpler install that runs on your web server using PHP, see Google Analytics for Status Board Server Edition.</description></item></channel></rss>