<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tools on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/tags/tools/</link><description>Recent content in Tools on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 11:02:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.com/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Good Tools Change</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/07/07/good-tools-change/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 11:02:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/07/07/good-tools-change/</guid><description>In Good Tools, James Bennett writes a compelling article on how his investment in learning his most used tool, emacs, has paid huge dividends in his productivity for years and years. I recommend you read it, his arguments are cogent and his points well founded and well made. He writes:
Good tools, for programmers, are investments: you give them your time and your brain up-front, and then they pay dividends for years on end.</description></item><item><title>Is it time to change tools?</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/16/is-it-time-to-change-tools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 18:15:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/16/is-it-time-to-change-tools/</guid><description>To improve is to change; to be perfect is to change often.
Winston Churchill
Every once in a while I wonder if my programming tools, languages and platforms need to be changed. Maybe, just maybe, the software mix I use every day needs to be shaken up.
And then my mind starts spinning in circles.
As we all do, I find myself using the same languages and tools over and over again.</description></item><item><title>Every 'The Best Programmers Editor' Review</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/14/every-the-best-programmers-editor-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 17:58:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/14/every-the-best-programmers-editor-review/</guid><description>I read a lot of programmer&amp;rsquo;s editor reviews and see a lot of arguments about which is best. Yet, essentially, they all do the same thing, help you program the way you want to. So here is my review of your favorite programmer&amp;rsquo;s editor for the Mac.
Choose your Editor: TextMate 2 | Sublime Text 2 | BBEdit | Chocolat | Vim | Emacs My EDITOR Review EDITOR is by far the best programmer&amp;rsquo;s editor ever.</description></item><item><title>A Coda 2 Use Case</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/12/a-coda-2-use-case/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 11:20:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/12/a-coda-2-use-case/</guid><description>I upgraded to Panic&amp;rsquo;s Coda 2 when it came out, and never used it. Unless it was to trigger a software update.
That was until last week.
Last week I was working on an odd project to create a set of web pages that would be hosted on a payment processor&amp;rsquo;s site, but must look and feel like they are running on the actual site. This was for some non-profits to enable them to accept credit-card donations and electronic payment of member fees.</description></item></channel></rss>