<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>iPhone on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/tags/iphone/</link><description>Recent content in iPhone on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 10:58:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.com/tags/iphone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scratched iPhones</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/10/10/scratched-iphones/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 10:58:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/10/10/scratched-iphones/</guid><description>There’s a big brouhaha in the news these days that new iPhone 5’s come scratched out of the box, and that the new aluminium backs scratch too easily. So much noise that Apple is trying to “fix” the problem by not shipping pre-scratched ones, and by telling people that scratching is normal for aluminium products.
I prefer Remy Labesque’s take back in 2011 in Aged to Perfection, the back of scratched iPhones can and does look beautiful.</description></item><item><title>Entitlement</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/09/28/entitlement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 14:29:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/09/28/entitlement/</guid><description>Excellent post by Aaron Mahnke called Entitlement about all those moaning about the new iPhone (although I think it applies to all new products), please read and share it:
Where is the sense of gratitude and wonder that we used to have? A tech company sells millions and millions of an amazing smart phone, but decided to create a new model by investing untold amounts of money and energy. And then they released it for the same price as the last model.</description></item><item><title>New iOS6 Cached Maps</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/09/24/new-ios6-cached-maps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 16:37:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/09/24/new-ios6-cached-maps/</guid><description>One feature I do like about the new Maps in iOS 6, the vectors and data are now cached. Seems the application caches the last viewed maps, so the GPS works rather well when offline.
Screenshot taken near Zushi station in Japan, with no WiFi or cellular data enabled.
Note also that the detail in semi-rural Japan seems pretty good.</description></item><item><title>iPhone is 5 today</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/06/29/iphone-is-5-today/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 19:18:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/06/29/iphone-is-5-today/</guid><description>Five years ago, the first iPhone went on sale. My, have mobile phones changed since then.
My Mobiles before the iPhone launch When I first came to the USA, the only phones I could get were pay-as-you-go bricks. After some time, I finally became eligible for a contract phone.
My first was the Verizon V710 flip phone (first left). It was sold as the first phone to allow bluetooth sync between the phone and your computer, so I got that one.</description></item><item><title>My iPhone Home Screen</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/04/26/my-iphone-home-screen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 09:22:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/04/26/my-iphone-home-screen/</guid><description>I have noticed of late a trend in people or sites showing off their iPhone home screens, the first page on your iPhone with the dock, and explaining why they rearranged the applications and icons. Some have even moved the Phone.app off their home screens.
They are all doing it, so it must be cool.
My home screen on the iPhone is factory original. All the applications are exactly in the same place that Apple put them when the iPhone was first set up.</description></item><item><title>iPhone Data Plan Follies</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/02/25/iphone-data-plan-follies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 10:25:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/02/25/iphone-data-plan-follies/</guid><description>This week, three stories came to my attention regarding iPhone data plans and usage: man wins $850 from AT&amp;amp;T for data throttling, Siri is ruining your cellphone service, and its all about the camera.
iPhone user wins $850 in throttling case Source: Judge awards iPhone user $850 in throttling case
In short, so a guy who was sold the unlimited AT&amp;amp;T data plan gets throttled, sues AT&amp;amp;T in small claims court and wins some money.</description></item></channel></rss>