<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/tags/web/</link><description>Recent content in Web on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 11:20:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.com/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Coda 2 Use Case</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/12/a-coda-2-use-case/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 11:20:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/12/a-coda-2-use-case/</guid><description>I upgraded to Panic&amp;rsquo;s Coda 2 when it came out, and never used it. Unless it was to trigger a software update.
That was until last week.
Last week I was working on an odd project to create a set of web pages that would be hosted on a payment processor&amp;rsquo;s site, but must look and feel like they are running on the actual site. This was for some non-profits to enable them to accept credit-card donations and electronic payment of member fees.</description></item><item><title>Reading the Archives</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/07/reading-the-archives/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 09:20:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/07/reading-the-archives/</guid><description>Most people when they click on a link to a new blog, read the linked article and move on elsewhere. Google Analytics records this as a bounce - a visitor comes in, reads a single page and leaves.
One of my habits when I come across a new blog is to read the archives. Almost every blogging platform has archives and almost every blogger makes these available.
But why read the archives?</description></item><item><title>Oldest Trace of You on the Internet</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/26/oldest-trace-of-you-on-the-internet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 10:20:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/26/oldest-trace-of-you-on-the-internet/</guid><description>For a lark, and in response to this tweet:
what's the oldest trace of yourself you can find on the internet?
&amp;mdash; Kyle McDonald (@kcimc) March 24, 2013 I started on the Internet in the late 1980&amp;rsquo;s when it was still called Arpanet. I connected our University of Cape Town UNIX boxes via UUCP to Rhodes University in South Africa which in turn used UUCP to talk to Oxford University in the UK, which in turn connected to one of the Ivy Leagues in the USA.</description></item><item><title>RSS Address Change</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/19/rss-address-change/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 19:23:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/19/rss-address-change/</guid><description>Update: This post has been updated with a new feed URL that will become the standard in future releases of Octopress. If you re-subscribed, I&amp;rsquo;d ask if you could please do it one more time. Thanks.
It looks like Google is about to kill off Feedburner, so its best if we get started on the transition. Going forward, I&amp;rsquo;ll be using Octopress&amp;rsquo; built-in RSS feed. Please re-subscribe to The Hiltmon RSS Feed at:</description></item><item><title>Cutting down on Web Tracking</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/18/cutting-down-on-web-tracking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 10:46:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/18/cutting-down-on-web-tracking/</guid><description>You may not know it, but lots of web sites use a variety of tricks to track you across the Internet, not just on the site you are currently browsing. These all depend on your browser talking to the tracker&amp;rsquo;s server without your knowledge or consent. These trackers use huge numbers of servers with different names and IP addresses to make it more difficult to stop them.
If you use a single browser all the time, plugins like Ghostery work very well.</description></item><item><title>Download Dreamhost Server Logs</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/10/download-dreamhost-server-logs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 14:38:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/10/download-dreamhost-server-logs/</guid><description>This site is hosted on Dreamhost, and I could not be happier with them. But some time ago, the engineers there decided to disable FTP access to the server logs. No reason given.
If you have a Dreamhost shared account, try it. ftp into your server using your favorite FTP client, click the logs folder, then your site folder, then http and you’ll get an error. This is because the http folder is actually a symlink to a private, readonly folder on the server that is inaccessible to FTP.</description></item><item><title>Add Web Clip Icons to Octopress</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/10/add-web-clip-icons-to-octopress/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 13:57:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/10/add-web-clip-icons-to-octopress/</guid><description>The default Octopress setup includes a favicon.png which enables you to place your own tiny icon to the left of the URL in most browsers. You should see a small blue cog there now.
Both Apple and Android phones also support saving a link to a site (called a web clip) on your phone as an icon. Over the past few days, it seems quite a few viewers of this site have added it as a web clip, but I had not provided good iconage.</description></item></channel></rss>