<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Computers on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/computers/</link><description>Recent content in Computers on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 11:25:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/computers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Workspace</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/04/28/my-workspace/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 11:25:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/04/28/my-workspace/</guid><description>I have no idea why I am sharing this, but this is my current workspace:
On and around it you will find (left-to-right-ish):
My original iPad 1 running Panic&amp;rsquo;s Status Board on a Twelve South Compass Stand for iPad. A Koncept Equo Gen 3 desk lamp, stylish and bright. An AT&amp;amp;T MicroCell so I can get Mobile Phone service at home in Manhattan! My iPad 3 WiFi 64GB, gray Apple smart cover.</description></item><item><title>1GHz Titanium PowerBook</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/12/31/1ghz-titanium-powerbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 11:01:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/12/31/1ghz-titanium-powerbook/</guid><description>It was about this time 10 years ago that I purchased my precious, a 1GHz Titanium Powerbook from a back street store in Akihabara (Electric Town) in Tokyo, Japan. I bought it based on a single viewing of another PowerBook because it ran UNIX with a GUI. Oh and it was thin and fast and beautiful.
It surely is the best device I ever owned.
I had been a Mac user in the early 1990&amp;rsquo;s, but, like most, I moved over to Windows for work.</description></item><item><title>Walled Gardens are Permeable</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/10/15/walled-gardens-are-permeable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 12:36:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/10/15/walled-gardens-are-permeable/</guid><description>There is an incredible amount of Fear, Uncertainty and Doubt (FUD) on the internet about walled gardens, or closed ecosystems, especially focussed on Apple and ignoring everyone else. The open versus closed ecosystem holy war is in full force, with a lot of words written in absolute and extreme terms. Yet the so-called walled garden systems appear to be most popular and most successful.
I believe that in reality these closed ecosystems actually have very permeable walls and that we&amp;rsquo;re really working in the middle ground between open and closed.</description></item><item><title>My first computer - Sinclair ZX81</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/08/01/my-first-computer-sinclair-zx81/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 14:24:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/08/01/my-first-computer-sinclair-zx81/</guid><description>With the Commodore 64 turning 30 today (See: BBC News - Commodore 64 turns 30: What do today&amp;rsquo;s kids make of it?), I started thinking about my first computer, the Sinclair ZX81 (see it on Wikipedia), also called the Timex Sinclair 1000 in the USA.
Photo of Sinclair ZX81, tv and tape (c) Mike Cattell on Flickr (because I have none).
The year would have been 1982, I was an awkward teenager, and this new device changed my world.</description></item><item><title>Joining the SSD Club</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/07/22/joining-the-ssd-club/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 09:32:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/07/22/joining-the-ssd-club/</guid><description>On Friday, I joined the SSD club. That’s the Solid State Drive club, not the Special School District or the Social Security Disability clubs. I installed a OWC Mercury Electra 3G 240GB SSD in my Mid-2009 MacBook Pro to replace my never working DVD drive.
I purchased the kit that included the bracket (they call it a data doubler), the tools and the SSD:
Installation was easy, I used the video and the manual that came with it.</description></item><item><title>Software will always trump Hardware</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/07/19/software-will-always-trump-hardware/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 18:59:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/07/19/software-will-always-trump-hardware/</guid><description>Shawn Blanc reviews the Nexus 7 tablet in Thoughts and Impressions of the Nexus 7, and concludes with a great point:
For me, when it comes down to it, software will always trump hardware. When I’m using a device like the Nexus 7 I want to know where the details are. Where is the magic? The fun? The incredible 3rd-party apps? It is because of these elements that the iPad is more than the sum of its parts while its competition continues to remains less than.</description></item><item><title>On the Nexus 7</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/06/28/on-the-nexus-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 09:07:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/06/28/on-the-nexus-7/</guid><description>Yesterday, Google announced the Nexus 7, their first hardware and software combination tablet.
In short, and in my opinion, they have created the reference platform for Android tablet development. Pair that with the Galaxy Nexus phone and you have the best Android pair since the iPhone/iPad duo, for development.
But until I need to develop for Android, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to buy one. I already have an iPad and an iPhone.</description></item><item><title>Unrepairable</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/06/17/unrepairable/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2012 14:27:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/06/17/unrepairable/</guid><description>Last week, Apple launched the new retina Macbook Pro. Which, of course, was immediately followed by a brouhaha (Definition: A noisy and overexcited critical response, display of interest, or trail of publicity.)
Kyle Wiens, who runs a web site called iFixit which creates videos for people who want to fix things, posted an article in Wired entitled The New MacBook Pro: Unfixable, Unhackable, Untenable claiming that the new laptop is unfixable by the general public, and that this is, of course, obviously &amp;ldquo;a very bad thing&amp;rdquo; and part of a trend that will destroy the tech industry as we know it.</description></item><item><title>The Last of the Workstations</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/06/03/the-last-of-the-workstations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2012 13:22:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/06/03/the-last-of-the-workstations/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I started this post a few days ago, before WWDC 2012, before Jim Dalrymple&amp;rsquo;s famous &amp;lsquo;No&amp;rsquo; to whether it will be discontinued (see &lt;a href="http://www.marco.org/2012/05/30/amplified-9">Marco&amp;rsquo;s note&lt;/a>), when I felt that Apple had finally given up on the Mac Pro. I&amp;rsquo;m posting it now because I really do love true workstation performance, and hope that the Mac Pro product line continues this tradition.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Is the current Mac Pro the last of the true workstations? I hope not. Apple has not updated this product line for years now, yet there is nothing else on the market today that provides the Mac Pro&amp;rsquo;s badass performance and expandability in the true workstation space.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apple Cinema HD Display circa 2003</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/05/16/apple-cinema-hd-display-circa-2003/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 16:26:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/05/16/apple-cinema-hd-display-circa-2003/</guid><description>That&amp;rsquo;s right kids, I am still using the old 23&amp;quot; Apple Cinema HD Display I purchased in 2003, 9 years ago, before Apple went all aluminium.
I use an ADB to DVI adapter to connect it to the Mac Pro. I love its matte screen, 1080p support and the fact that I have to prop it up using old Final Cut manuals. It still works great, though.</description></item><item><title>Top of the Line</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/03/09/top-of-the-line/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2012 15:12:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/03/09/top-of-the-line/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m not rich, but when I buy technology, I always get the top-of-the-line model within my product range. Why? Longevity and Productivity. I choose the range to suit my needs and skill levels. And the long-term benefits of productivity and time savings way exceed the short-term incremental cost.
All my devices last forever because I purchased the top-of-the-line within the range I needed. In 1998, I purchased the best Dell Inspiron laptop, it lasted until 2003 when I moved to the best Titanium PowerBook, which lasted until 2009 when I acquired my current MacBook Pro.</description></item></channel></rss>