<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TimeToCall on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/tags/timetocall/</link><description>Recent content in TimeToCall on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 12:41:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.com/tags/timetocall/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Direct Marketing your App to Tip Lines</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/28/direct-marketing-your-app-to-tip-lines/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 12:41:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/28/direct-marketing-your-app-to-tip-lines/</guid><description>In TimeToCall - After One Month, I stated that my next marketing experiment would be to send a PR style email to popular press site tip lines to see if they worked. In parallel, and unbeknownst to me, Christian Tietze was doing the same thing, just paying for it (See Sales and AppLaunch.us experience for Calendar Paste, worth a read and reminding me to post this).
The results are:
12 PR messages sent (see the actual message sent at the bottom of this post) 1 delivery failure (so I used a backup address) 2 robo-responders indicating that the emails were received, thank you 0 reviews 0 posts about the product 0 requests for promo codes 0 responses 0 sales To be clear, I do not blame any of these folks for the lack of response (and I did not really expect any).</description></item><item><title>TimeToCall - After One Month</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/07/timetocall-after-one-month/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 14:46:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/07/timetocall-after-one-month/</guid><description>TimeToCall is a simple, universal iOS application I developed to help people choose the best time to call when calling internationally. This is a follow-on to a 10 part (and growing) series I wrote about the thinking and work done. My goal is to share just how much effort it really does take to craft an iPhone app and ship it. I hope this series helps you to understand why it costs so much and takes so long to create beautiful software.</description></item><item><title>TimeToCall Demo Video</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/05/timetocall-demo-video/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 15:32:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/05/timetocall-demo-video/</guid><description>In preparation for the massive PR campaign that will never happen, I created a demo video of TimeToCall, showing off the new &amp;ldquo;drag down slider&amp;rdquo;, and added it to the product page. I am hoping v1.0.1 gets approved soon so you can all play with time.
Why make a Video? There is no trial on the App Store, so the next best thing is a quick video to help people decide whether the App does what they want.</description></item><item><title>TimeToCall - First Updates Coming Soon</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/28/timetocall-first-updates-coming-soon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 17:57:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/28/timetocall-first-updates-coming-soon/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve received some great feedback and a few bug reports on TimeToCall and spent some time trying to make it a better product. The next decision is when to pull the trigger and put the first update through the App Store review process.
Changes The two big changes I have made so far are a more accurate slider and the time now toggle.
In the original release, I set the time slider to jump to 15 minute increments to make it easier to hit a &amp;lsquo;zero&amp;rsquo; time.</description></item><item><title>TimeToCall - After One Week</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/14/timetocall-after-one-week/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 07:56:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/14/timetocall-after-one-week/</guid><description>TimeToCall is a simple, universal iOS application I developed to help people choose the best time to call when calling internationally. This is a follow-on to a 10 part (and growing) series I wrote about the thinking and work done. My goal is to share just how much effort it really does take to craft an iPhone app and ship it. I hope this series helps you to understand why it costs so much and takes so long to create beautiful software.</description></item><item><title>TimeToCall - Shipping</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/07/timetocall-shipping/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 08:18:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/07/timetocall-shipping/</guid><description>TimeToCall is a simple, universal iOS application I developed to help people choose the best time to call when calling internationally. This is part 10, the last part in a series of posts about the thinking and work done. My goal is to share just how much effort it really does take to craft an iOS app and ship it. I hope this series helps you to understand why it costs so much and takes so long to create beautiful software.</description></item><item><title>TimeToCall - Dawdle to the Finish</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/06/timetocall-dawdle-to-the-finish/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 10:28:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/06/timetocall-dawdle-to-the-finish/</guid><description>TimeToCall is a simple, universal iOS application I developed to help people choose the best time to call when calling internationally. This is part 9 in a series of posts about the thinking and work done. My goal is to share just how much effort it really does take to craft an iPhone app and ship it. I hope this series helps you to understand why it costs so much and takes so long to create beautiful software.</description></item><item><title>TimeToCall - The MacGuffin</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/05/timetocall-the-macguffin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 10:15:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/05/timetocall-the-macguffin/</guid><description>TimeToCall is a simple, universal iOS application I developed to help people choose the best time to call when calling internationally. This is part 8 in a series of posts about the thinking and work done. My goal is to share just how much effort it really does take to craft an iPhone app and ship it. I hope this series helps you to understand why it costs so much and takes so long to create beautiful software.</description></item><item><title>TimeToCall - Polishing the App</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/04/timetocall-polishing-the-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 09:34:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/04/timetocall-polishing-the-app/</guid><description>TimeToCall is a simple, universal iOS application I developed to help people choose the best time to call when calling internationally. This is part 7 in a series of posts about the thinking and work done. My goal is to share just how much effort it really does take to craft an iPhone app and ship it. I hope this series helps you to understand why it costs so much and takes so long to create beautiful software.</description></item><item><title>TimeToCall - Sweating the Details</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/03/timetocall-sweating-the-details/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 13:07:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/03/timetocall-sweating-the-details/</guid><description>TimeToCall is a simple, universal iOS application I developed to help people choose the best time to call when calling internationally. This is part 6 in a series of posts about the thinking and work done. My goal is to share just how much effort it really does take to craft an iPhone app and ship it. I hope this series helps you to understand why it costs so much and takes so long to create beautiful software.</description></item><item><title>TimeToCall - Good and Bad Times to Call</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/02/timetocall-good-and-bad-times-to-call/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 11:38:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/02/timetocall-good-and-bad-times-to-call/</guid><description>TimeToCall is a simple, universal iOS application I developed to help people choose the best time to call when calling internationally. This is part 5 in a series of posts about the thinking and work done. My goal is to share just how much effort it really does take to craft an iPhone app and ship it. I hope this series helps you to understand why it costs so much and takes so long to create beautiful software.</description></item><item><title>TimeToCall - Presenting the Clock</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/01/timetocall-presenting-the-clock/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 10:22:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/01/timetocall-presenting-the-clock/</guid><description>TimeToCall is a simple, universal iOS application I developed to help people choose the best time to call when calling internationally. This is part 4 in a series of posts about the thinking and work done. My goal is to share just how much effort it really does take to craft an iPhone app and ship it. I hope this series helps you to understand why it costs so much and takes so long to create beautiful software.</description></item><item><title>TimeToCall - The Biggest Design Decision</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/01/31/timetocall-the-biggest-design-decision/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 11:42:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/01/31/timetocall-the-biggest-design-decision/</guid><description>TimeToCall is a simple, universal iOS application I developed to help people choose the best time to call when calling internationally. This is part 3 in a series of posts about the thinking and work done. My goal is to share just how much effort it really does take to craft an iPhone app and ship it. I hope this series helps you to understand why it costs so much and takes so long to create beautiful software.</description></item><item><title>TimeToCall - Building the Core</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/01/30/timetocall-building-the-core/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 11:29:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/01/30/timetocall-building-the-core/</guid><description>TimeToCall is a simple, universal iOS application I developed to help people choose the best time to call when calling internationally. This is part 2 in a series of posts about the thinking and work done. My goal is to share just how much effort it really does take to craft an iPhone app and ship it. I hope this series helps you to understand why it costs so much and takes so long to create beautiful software.</description></item><item><title>TimeToCall - The Effort and the Return</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/01/29/timetocall-the-effort-and-the-return/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 19:33:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/01/29/timetocall-the-effort-and-the-return/</guid><description>TimeToCall is a simple, universal iOS application I developed to help people choose the best time to call when calling internationally. This is part 1 in a series of posts about the thinking and work done. My goal is to share just how much effort it really does take to craft an iPhone app and ship it. I hope this series helps you to understand why it costs so much and takes so long to create beautiful software.</description></item></channel></rss>