<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 18:45:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The One-Person Product</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/05/20/the-one-person-product/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 18:45:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/05/20/the-one-person-product/</guid><description>Marco Arment, writing about David Karp, founder of Tumblr, in The One-Person Product. Not only is this piece well written, it is an amazing perspective of Tumblr from the inside. But, for me, the salient point and the highest praise in the piece goes to David Karp, the founder and visionary:
David has an impeccable sense of what’s best for Tumblr, and he doesn’t need anyone else telling him what’s best for the product.</description></item><item><title>Avoiding the Blogger Trap</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/05/08/avoiding-the-blogger-trap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 10:43:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/05/08/avoiding-the-blogger-trap/</guid><description>I totally agree with Marco in Avoiding the blogger trap:
People aren’t so one-sided. Everyone has a life that goes much deeper than the topics on their blogs.
and
This site represents me, and I’m random and eccentric and interested in a wide variety of subjects.
This site is me, with a hodge podge of posts ranging from opinion pieces, news, geeky ideas, advice, links, jokes, setups and productivity.</description></item><item><title>$60 million to aquihire me</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/03/28/60-million-to-aquihire-me/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 11:55:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/03/28/60-million-to-aquihire-me/</guid><description>So this week, Yahoo paid $30 million to acquire Summly and it&amp;rsquo;s 17 year old founder Nick D&amp;rsquo;Aloisio (just Google it).
The way I read the deal:
Summly and its product is going to be shut down. So it&amp;rsquo;s not the product they wanted. Nick only has to hang around for 18 months to get all his money. So it&amp;rsquo;s not the founder they wanted. Summly licensed its technology from someone else, so Yahoo is not getting any IP in the deal either.</description></item><item><title>Long on Apple</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/03/19/long-on-apple/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 11:29:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/03/19/long-on-apple/</guid><description>Chris Umiastowski in Apple investors: How to stay sane by staying long via iMore:
Realize that you will never have an information advantage over the pros. Most information is geared to short term results anyway. Just don’t pay attention to short term news and rumours when it comes to investing. It won’t help you. Buy a stock for your own reasons and sell when those reasons are no longer true.</description></item><item><title>I'm doing it wrong: Dropbox buys Mailbox</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/03/19/im-doing-it-wrong-dropbox-buys-mailbox/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 10:17:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/03/19/im-doing-it-wrong-dropbox-buys-mailbox/</guid><description>On my tweet stream today:
@jnack Makes me wonder why I’ve been wasting years developing a sustainable product through many mature versions.
&amp;mdash; Marco Arment (@marcoarment) March 18, 2013 Anyone got ideas for a revenue-free product I can make and sell for 100mm?
Follow the author as @hiltmon on Twitter and @hiltmon on App.Net. Mute #xpost on one.</description></item><item><title>Windows Phone 8 support will expire before your phone contract does</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/03/18/windows-phone-8-support-will-expire-before-your-phone-contract-does/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 12:10:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/03/18/windows-phone-8-support-will-expire-before-your-phone-contract-does/</guid><description>In a seriously bone-headed move, Microsoft has quietly announced that their mobile Operating Systems will only be supported and updated for 18 months:
Microsoft will make updates available for the Operating System on your phone, including security updates, for a period of 18 months after the lifecycle start date. Distribution of the updates may be controlled by the mobile operator or the phone manufacturer from which you purchased your phone.</description></item><item><title>Premature BlackBerry Sales Analysis by Forbes</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/03/15/premature-blackberry-sales-analysis-by-forbes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 09:46:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/03/15/premature-blackberry-sales-analysis-by-forbes/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this for a friend who tweeted this article to me. Feel free to listen in. Mate, this in an intervention, don&amp;rsquo;t believe what you read in Forbes. Please.
Lets take yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post Nearly Half Of BlackBerry Z10 Buyers Switching From iPhone And Android by Agustino Fontevecchia.
BlackBerry’s new smartphone is stealing iPhone and Android users, according to a recent note by RBC Capital markets, which shows 45% of those buying Z10s converted from the two leading operating systems.</description></item><item><title>Also Destroyed the Ecosystem</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/03/14/destroyed-the-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 17:56:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/03/14/destroyed-the-ecosystem/</guid><description>Aldo Cortesi in Google, destroyer of ecosystems writes:
The truth is this: Google destroyed the RSS feed reader ecosystem with a subsidized product, stifling its competitors and killing innovation.
Erhem, see also:
Amazon → book stores Amazon → music stores Amazon → video stores Starbucks → coffee shops Best Buy → Appliance stores Home Depot → Hardware stores Luxottica → Eyewear LVMH → Luxury goods Follow the author as @hiltmon on Twitter and @hiltmon on App.</description></item><item><title>Guessing the Wall Street Journal Agenda for Apple</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/03/12/guessing-the-wall-street-journal-agenda-for-apple/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 15:52:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/03/12/guessing-the-wall-street-journal-agenda-for-apple/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m not a subscriber to the Wall Street Journal, but I have noted the past few months that the WSJ seems to issue regular negative news, no, opinions, no, rumors, no, rubbish on Apple.
So I ran a test, I Googled wsj apple.
Here are the headlines that came up. I only read the blurb because the content is behind a paywall, and so include my guess as to what I expect would be in the article (and know wasn&amp;rsquo;t):</description></item><item><title>Spent more on Patents than R&amp;D?</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/10/10/spent-more-on-patents-than-r/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 10:12:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/10/10/spent-more-on-patents-than-r/</guid><description>Ian Betteridge @ianbetteridge takes the New York Times down in Did Apple and Google really spend more on patents than R&amp;amp;D?, in response to the NYT article The iEconomy: Apple and Technology Manufacturing (Subscription required):
Read the NYT piece, and you would think that the technology market has shifted from being about research and development of new products to being about acquisition of patents. Given that this is based on a single year, when some very big patent portfolios came on the market in one-off deals that aren’t likely to be repeated in the future, that’s a long way from the truth.</description></item><item><title>Where is the International News</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/08/20/where-is-the-international-news/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 10:29:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/08/20/where-is-the-international-news/</guid><description>Claire Belinski explains in the badly titled How to Read Today&amp;rsquo;s Unbelievably Bad News :: Gatestone Institute where good international news coverage has gone.
Something has gone very wrong in American coverage of news from abroad. It is shoddy, lazy, riddled with mistakes, and excessively simplistic.
Above all, it is absent.
Mainly this is why:
In the event of a massive breaking story—such as the uprisings in Tahrir Square—the networks parachute their people in.</description></item><item><title>AT&amp;T effs users again</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/08/18/att-effs-users-again/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 12:41:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/08/18/att-effs-users-again/</guid><description>The beard, Jim Dalrymple nails it in AT&amp;amp;T fucks users… again:
“Our network sucks balls. If we tried to let all of you rapid iPhone users have FaceTime, our network would take a firey crash into Hell. Many of the executives that have been too goddamn cheap to upgrade the network are now scared shitless that they will lose their cushy bonuses. So we decided to fuck our users.”</description></item><item><title>Hipstamatic fires its devs</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/08/17/hipstamatic-fires-its-devs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 14:08:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/08/17/hipstamatic-fires-its-devs/</guid><description>Of all the stupid things to do, Hipstamatic fired its 3 devs, 1 designer and writer yesterday. Here’s how it played out on Twitter.
So in case you didn’t get the memo. Entire team laid off. 3 devs, 1 designer, 1 writer. Some of THE best people I’ve ever worked with…
Jonathan Wight
This is a company making 22 million dollars this year (according to The Verge here). And expects to continue without its creatives!</description></item><item><title>Talent Acquisitions and Product Casualties</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/07/22/talent-acquisitions-and-product-casualties/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 10:20:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/07/22/talent-acquisitions-and-product-casualties/</guid><description>This week, Google purchased Sparrow SAS, the company that made the very popular Sparrow mail application for Mac and iOS. But they did not buy the company for the product, the bought the company for its people - the talent. Sparrow, the product, is done for.
Facebook also executed a talent acquisition on Acrylic, makers of Pulp, an RSS reader, and Wallet, a secure store. Both these products are now dead.</description></item><item><title>Two kinds of innovations in tech</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/07/19/two-kinds-of-innovations-in-tech/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 19:07:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/07/19/two-kinds-of-innovations-in-tech/</guid><description>Kevin Kelleher, writing for ReadWriteWeb in How AT&amp;amp;T &amp;amp; Verizon Learned to Stop Worrying and Love Data Hogs about AT&amp;amp;T&amp;rsquo;s new pricing model, nails the conclusion in regards to the carriers in the USA:
There are two kinds of innovations in tech. One that is often celebrated – the creation of great new things people will gladly pay for – and another that few companies will brag about – finding new ways to get people to pay for something they already have.</description></item><item><title>Unrepairable</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/06/17/unrepairable/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2012 14:27:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/06/17/unrepairable/</guid><description>Last week, Apple launched the new retina Macbook Pro. Which, of course, was immediately followed by a brouhaha (Definition: A noisy and overexcited critical response, display of interest, or trail of publicity.)
Kyle Wiens, who runs a web site called iFixit which creates videos for people who want to fix things, posted an article in Wired entitled The New MacBook Pro: Unfixable, Unhackable, Untenable claiming that the new laptop is unfixable by the general public, and that this is, of course, obviously &amp;ldquo;a very bad thing&amp;rdquo; and part of a trend that will destroy the tech industry as we know it.</description></item><item><title>The news routine</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/04/19/the-news-routine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 13:58:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/04/19/the-news-routine/</guid><description>Twitter, Facebook, RSS, all wonderful services, all bombarding us with information, all taking time and attention away from things we should be doing. In order to remain productive, I have moved these services onto the iPad and created a reading routine to eliminate the temptation to waste hours on these services.
Two screens are now one Previously, I did all my work on my Mac Pro with dual 24&amp;quot; Dell monitors.</description></item><item><title>Don't Panic - Flashback Trojan</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/04/12/dont-panic-flashback-trojan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 10:05:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/04/12/dont-panic-flashback-trojan/</guid><description>Please read the following list in its entirety before acting:
600,000+ OS X Computers have been infected by the Flashback Trojan In percentage terms, that&amp;rsquo;s more than the largest virus infection on Windows ever You should panic, the &amp;ldquo;running down a corridor screaming with your hair on fire&amp;rdquo; kind of panic You should download, install and run all the Flashback removal tools (Links: here or here) You should buy and install at least one anti-virus package immediately, maybe two.</description></item></channel></rss>