<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sanity Saver on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/sanity-saver/</link><description>Recent content in Sanity Saver on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 14:56:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/sanity-saver/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sanity Saver: Detox expands t.co links</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/10/14/detox-expands-t-dot-co-links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 14:56:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/10/14/detox-expands-t-dot-co-links/</guid><description>If you use Twitter and click on t.co links, or use Google search and follow their links, chances are your browser history is a mess of t.co/C*R@A%P&amp;amp; or google.com/S$H@I*T#. Which means there is no way to use your browser history to find that page you just saw (or saw a few days ago) and accidentally closed. And autocomplete does not work either.
Shaun Inman (of Mint and The Last Rocket fame) created a Safari extension called Detox a while ago that automatically expands those pesky t.</description></item><item><title>Sanity Saver - Ticks and Crosses</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/05/28/sanity-saver-ticks-and-crosses/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 14:11:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/05/28/sanity-saver-ticks-and-crosses/</guid><description>Sanity Savers are quick tips that help you stay sane when using your computer.
I often create point form lists of things, whether planning a post or a coding sprint or a client activity. And to keep track of which points in the list are done and which will not be done, or what is right and what is wrong, I like to use ✓ and ✗ symbols.
I use them so frequently and am so lazy that even typing ,,tick and ,,cross TextExpander expansions are too much effort.</description></item><item><title>Sanity Saver: NoMoreiTunes</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/01/19/sanity-saver-nomoreitunes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 12:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/01/19/sanity-saver-nomoreitunes/</guid><description>Sanity Savers are quick tips that help you stay sane when using your computer.
I really don’t like it when you web browse to the App Store (iOS or Mac), it also launches iTunes or the App Store App on top. If I want to buy the app, I’ll click myself, I do not want my browsing flow to be interrupted by the launch of another application.
The NoMoreiTunes Safari Extension prevents this from happening.</description></item></channel></rss>