<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Text Editors on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/text-editors/</link><description>Recent content in Text Editors on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 14:07:30 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/text-editors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>More TextMate 2 Basics</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2014/01/20/more-textmate-2-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 14:07:30 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2014/01/20/more-textmate-2-basics/</guid><description>Previously, I wrote about the TextMate 2 Basics that I use all the time, and I recommend you read that post first. This post follows up with a mish-mash of more tools, ideas and tricks that I also use surprisingly frequently.
Text Tools TextMate 2 tries to reduce the number of keystrokes you need to make to generate good code. There are many ways it does this but today I want to talk about auto-pairs and completions.</description></item><item><title>TextMate 2 Basics</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/11/09/textmate-2-basics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/11/09/textmate-2-basics/</guid><description>I have been using TextMate for years as my primary programmer&amp;rsquo;s editor, but it turns out that I only use a subset of its amazing features. I&amp;rsquo;ve been speaking with users of other awesome programmer&amp;rsquo;s editors and they wanted to know what it is in TextMate that I love so much and keeps me using it.
So here are the basic parts of TextMate 2 that I use regularly. Maybe you can divine some tips from it.</description></item><item><title>Every 'The Best Programmers Editor' Review</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/05/14/every-the-best-programmers-editor-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 17:58:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/05/14/every-the-best-programmers-editor-review/</guid><description>function setEditor(editor, url) { var elements = document.getElementsByClassName('editor-span'); for (var i = 0; i ' + editor + ''; } return false; } onload = function() { setEditor('TextMate 2', 'http://www.macromates.com/'); } I read a lot of programmer&amp;rsquo;s editor reviews and see a lot of arguments about which is best. Yet, essentially, they all do the same thing, help you program the way you want to. So here is my review of your favorite programmer&amp;rsquo;s editor for the Mac.</description></item><item><title>My TextMate 2 Setup</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/04/15/my-textmate-2-setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 14:42:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/04/15/my-textmate-2-setup/</guid><description>&lt;p>I switched back to &lt;a href="https://github.com/textmate/textmate">TextMate 2&lt;/a> from &lt;a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/2">Sublime Text 2&lt;/a> full time a while back and I am really happy with the way I have it looking and working. My &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/08/14/my-sublime-text-2-setup/">My Sublime Text 2 Setup&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; post is quite popular, so I though I&amp;rsquo;d create the same for TextMate 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="images/textmate-themes.jpg" width="600" height="240"/>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Sharing nvAlt Notes with Ulysses III</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/04/05/sharing-nvalt-notes-with-ulysses-iii/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 10:49:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/04/05/sharing-nvalt-notes-with-ulysses-iii/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m testing out Ulysses III for writing and so far I am finding it postively interesting for a 1.0 rewrite. One thing I wanted to try was to use it for notes alongside nvAlt.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how to share notes between Ulysses III and nvAlt.
In Ulysses III, click the plus icon on the bottom left (1) and choose Add External Source... (2). Choose the folder in Dropbox where you store your nvAlt plain text notes, then click Open.</description></item><item><title>Multiple Themes in TextMate 2</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/02/22/multiple-themes-in-textmate-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 18:02:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/02/22/multiple-themes-in-textmate-2/</guid><description>One thing I like to do is to have different themes for different file types in my text editor. That way, at a glance, I can guess what kind of file a text-filled window contains, especially when zoomed out using Mission Control. I’ve been using Custom Language Preferences in BBEdit preferences to set up the color scheme for each file type there, and I have set up Multiple Themes in Sublime Text 2 previously.</description></item><item><title>CriticMarkup Bundle for TextMate 2</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/02/15/criticmarkup-bundle-for-textmate-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 12:38:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/02/15/criticmarkup-bundle-for-textmate-2/</guid><description>Update: Christian Tietze (@DivineDominion) has created a bundle that&amp;rsquo;s included in the official toolkit, so I contributed my bundle&amp;rsquo;s commands to that, and will be using and contributing to that one from now on. Get the full toolkit at CriticMarkup-toolkit or just the TextMate bundle at criticmarkup.tmbundle. I&amp;rsquo;ve already taken my repo down to prevent confusion.
Recently, @macdrifter and @themindfulbit announced CriticMarkup, a way for authors and editors to track changes to documents in plain text.</description></item><item><title>RVM in TextMate 2</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/01/16/rvm-in-textmate-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 20:04:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/01/16/rvm-in-textmate-2/</guid><description>I use Ruby Version Manager (rvm) to manage the interpreters and gemsets for all of my projects. But the default install of TextMate 2 uses the system ruby interpreter for internal command execution as well as for external runs. Here is how to use your rvm environment for both.
tl;dr: Set the TM_RUBY variable in preferences or your ~/.tm_properties file to the path returned by which rvm-auto-ruby and restart. That will set the internal runner.</description></item><item><title>Back to TextMate 2</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/01/14/back-to-textmate-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 22:01:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/01/14/back-to-textmate-2/</guid><description>I spent the latter half of 2012 trying out new programmer’s editors, getting them set up the way I like and getting productive in them. This was no fly-by-night few-hour test, it was full-monty Rails development work for months. Lots of shell scripts, file manipulations, formats, different programming languages, different platforms, all my programming activities.
I tried BBEdit for programming, and it is good. BBEdit remains my text editing and file manipulation tool of choice and I suspect it always will be.</description></item><item><title>Multi-Platform Editing is Sublime</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/11/26/multi-platform-editing-is-sublime/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 20:37:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/11/26/multi-platform-editing-is-sublime/</guid><description>One of the best things about the Sublime Text 2 license is that it&amp;rsquo;s a per-user license. This allows you to run it on all computers where you are the primary user. And since Sublime Text 2 is multi-platform, that means on all the operating systems you use as well.
For example, in my case, I can and do run Sublime Text 2 on
My laptop Macintosh which is my regular workhorse.</description></item><item><title>Multiple Themes in Sublime Text 2</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/11/07/multiple-themes-in-sublime-text-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 15:09:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/11/07/multiple-themes-in-sublime-text-2/</guid><description>One thing I like to do is to have different themes for different file types in my text editor. That way, at a glance, I can guess what kind of file a text-filled window contains, especially when zoomed out using Mission Control. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Custom Language Preferences in BBEdit preferences to set up the color scheme for each file type there. TextMate 2 users, check out Multiple Themes in TextMate 2.</description></item><item><title>BBEdit still Rules</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/10/10/bbedit-still-rules/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 09:48:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/10/10/bbedit-still-rules/</guid><description>Lovely article on how the stalwart classic BBEdit still rules by Andy Ihnatko (@ihnatko) on Macworld today, entitled Mac classics: Why BBEdit rules
“BBEdit’s still important because at its essential core, it’s a tool for working with text,” says Rich Siegel, Bare Bones Software’s founder and CEO. “Not text for presentation, as in a word processor or page-layout application, but rather text as data supplied to other software: code for compilers and interpreters, markup and Web applications for Web browsers, log files and data tables for analysis, and for any tool that inhales raw text and turns it into something else.</description></item><item><title>Stop with the old Text Editors already</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/10/08/stop-with-the-old-text-editors-already/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 19:11:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/10/08/stop-with-the-old-text-editors-already/</guid><description>Over the past few years, it has become a thing to stop using IDE’s and modern text editors in favor of Vim. I understand older programmers using Vim out of habit, but the new generation of programmers? I don’t get it. Every-time I write about text editors, this growing group tweets to give modern GUI editors up and switch to old trusty rusty crusty terminal-based Vim.
Stop it! I’m not going to do that.</description></item><item><title>Text Editor Addict</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/08/25/text-editor-addict/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 13:10:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/08/25/text-editor-addict/</guid><description>Hi, my name is Hilton and maybe, just maybe, I am a text editor addict.
&amp;ldquo;Hello Hilton&amp;rdquo; you all say.
I seem to have a lot of text manipulation tools on my devices. Of course, I don’t think I have too many, but most people only seem to have one. You see, to me, each one has it’s own use, it’s the best tool for it’s job, that’s why I have and use it.</description></item><item><title>My Sublime Text 2 Setup</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/08/14/my-sublime-text-2-setup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 12:38:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/08/14/my-sublime-text-2-setup/</guid><description>I have been using Sublime Text 2 for a month or so now, and I still do not love it. Here’s hoping TextMate 2 gets it’s game on. But at least I have it working closer to the way I want it to work and look now. Here are the minor changes I have made to make it work for me and how it compares to TextMate 2 (Updated: See My TextMate 2 Setup - The Hiltmon).</description></item><item><title>Textmate 2 is now Open Source</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/08/09/textmate-2-is-now-open-source/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 11:07:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/08/09/textmate-2-is-now-open-source/</guid><description>My favorite programmers editor of all time, TextMate, recently updated to TextMate 2 Alpha. I’ve been using the alpha for a while, still love it, but it&amp;rsquo;s an alpha release and therefore buggy and slow. So I’ve been trying out Sublime Text 2 as a replacement. So far, I switch between TextMate 2 Alpha and Sublime Text 2 daily, only because closing the last tab in TextMate 2 closes the darn project editor and that annoys me.</description></item><item><title>Setting up BBEdit for Markdown</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/08/03/setting-up-bbedit-for-markdown/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 11:50:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/08/03/setting-up-bbedit-for-markdown/</guid><description>Two advanced settings are needed to make BBEdit treat all new documents as Markdown format, and to save with the correct file extension. They are:
defaults write com.barebones.bbedit PreferredFilenameExtension_Markdown -string &amp;#34;markdown&amp;#34; defaults write com.barebones.bbedit DefaultLanguageNameForNewDocuments Markdown If you use TextWrangler, replace the “bbedit” in the above with “textwrangler”. But I’d recommend purchasing BBEdit instead.</description></item><item><title>Text Editing Fonts and Colors</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/02/23/text-editing-fonts-and-colors/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 20:33:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/02/23/text-editing-fonts-and-colors/</guid><description>In The Markdown Mindset I described how I use a variety of different editors to write Markdown in different contexts. I also use different fonts and color schemes to help me differentiate as I go along.
For the record, everything was done in Monaco a few years ago.
Cousine Blogging is done in Byword using Cousine 15pt and the light theme. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty close to Nitti Light as used in iAWriter, but has variable sizing and is free from Google.</description></item></channel></rss>