<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Social on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/tags/social/</link><description>Recent content in Social on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 08:47:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.com/tags/social/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Twitter ADN and #xpost</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/26/using-twitter-adn-and-xpost/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 08:47:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/26/using-twitter-adn-and-xpost/</guid><description>I think I have finally figured out how I want to use App.Net and Twitter . Given my low follower counts on both, and the different follower groups I have on each, I should get away with it.
TL;DR: Follow me on both, no more cross-posting anything except blog post announcements, mute #xpost on one service to prevent duplicates. (Really? A TL;DR here! For an article this short? Where the &amp;ldquo;Too Long; Don&amp;rsquo;t Read&amp;rdquo; is about the same length as the post.</description></item><item><title>Workable Social Network Connection Heuristics</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/01/12/workable-social-network-connection-heuristics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 21:35:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/01/12/workable-social-network-connection-heuristics/</guid><description>I’m not sure how other people decide these things, but I have created my own heuristics as to whom I connect with on different social networks. In case you wish to blame me for your decisions — you’re welcome — here they are:
Family and Friends: These are blood relatives, friends I see socially on a regular basis, and old friends from way back — basically the people who accept me for who I am and I can share my more embarrassing and private moments with.</description></item><item><title>Depersonalize because you can’t quit</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/12/18/depersonalize-because-you-cant-quit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 12:58:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/12/18/depersonalize-because-you-cant-quit/</guid><description>My Twitter stream today is full of people quitting Instagram because of the new Terms of Service, see You’re the Advertisement. Six months ago, it was Twitter, and six months before that it was Facebook. Quitting over privacy.
Except they didn’t quit. They are all still on Twitter and Facebook and will remain on Instagram, because we, their friends are still there and the service remains awesomely useful.
If you are worried about privacy, but wish to remain on these services, just depersonalize.</description></item><item><title>You’re the Advertisement</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/12/17/youre-the-advertisement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 16:03:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/12/17/youre-the-advertisement/</guid><description>It used to be said that:
If you pay for a product, you’re a customer. If you don’t, you’re the product.
Now its getting worse. The new Instagram Terms of Use make you the advertisement for any unknown third party product. Anyone can pay Instagram to use your user name, your image, and your photos to advertise their product to anyone else, without your knowledge or consent.
Some or all of the Service may be supported by advertising revenue.</description></item><item><title>RIP Twitter</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/08/17/rip-twitter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 08:26:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/08/17/rip-twitter/</guid><description>“I wish to complain about this parrot what I purchased not half an hour ago from this very boutique.”
In March, Ryan Sarver, Platform Lead at Twitter speaking with MG Siegler on Techcrunch in Twitter Drops The Ecosystem Hammer: Don&amp;rsquo;t Try To Compete With Us On Clients, Focus On Data And Verticals:
We need to move to a less fragmented world, where every user can experience Twitter in a consistent way.</description></item><item><title>App.Net Funded</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/08/13/app-dot-net-funded/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 12:56:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/08/13/app-dot-net-funded/</guid><description>Today, App.Net got funded. Not many of us expected that to happen, but it did, and we’re happy to pay our $50 or $100 to kick it off. Most reports are reporting this service as a paid Twitter clone, and yes, that’s part of it. But the goals are bigger:
You are not the product: The product in Twitter is you, because it’s free. On App.Net, you are paying for the ID and the service and the access.</description></item><item><title>You're being stalked</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/03/27/youre-being-stalked/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 10:20:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/03/27/youre-being-stalked/</guid><description>In the same vein as an earlier article on my blog, Giving Yourself Away With a Facebook Login, Alexis Madrigal writing in the atlantic in I&amp;rsquo;m Being Followed: How Google—and 104 Other Companies—Are Tracking Me on the Web quotes Joe Turow saying:
If a company can follow your behavior in the digital environment &amp;ndash; an environment that potentially includes your mobile phone and television set &amp;ndash; its claim that you are &amp;ldquo;anonymous&amp;rdquo; is meaningless.</description></item><item><title>Giving yourself away with a Facebook Login</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/03/24/giving-yourself-away-with-a-facebook-login/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 12:11:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/03/24/giving-yourself-away-with-a-facebook-login/</guid><description>Applications that require a Facebook login are doing so to gain access to you, your name, your friends, your location, your personal details. They are not using the login because they are too lazy to create their own.
Hilton Lipschitz, right here right now
My wife asked me why I deleted Draw Something this week, as we were both enjoying drawing pictures with each other. I told her that Zynga purchased them, who Zynga were and why I did not want them to have access to my information.</description></item><item><title>Apple and Facebook</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/02/22/apple-and-facebook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 14:05:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/02/22/apple-and-facebook/</guid><description>Ben Parr in Cnet&amp;rsquo;s Apple vs. Facebook: Why users are the losers gets it wrong!
In the article, he postulates that Apple&amp;rsquo;s favorite social media service is Twitter and that Apple just hates Facebook (really?). He then explains there is no integration between Apple and Facebook because of some old Ping issues and some HP rubbish and some unsubstantiated hatred. Then he mentions that there actually is some Facebook integration, but its sandboxed in iPhoto.</description></item></channel></rss>