<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Carriers on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/tags/carriers/</link><description>Recent content in Carriers on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 17:23:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.com/tags/carriers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The myth of the wireless spectrum crisis</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/10/22/the-myth-of-the-wireless-spectrum-crisis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 17:23:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/10/22/the-myth-of-the-wireless-spectrum-crisis/</guid><description>Great article by Tim Farrar, a real pro on Gigaom entitled The myth of the wireless spectrum crisis, presents the fact that wireless data growth has stalled because of tiered pricing, low caps and market saturation instead of growing out of control:
However, underlying the statistics are numbers that tell a far different story: in fact, there was a dramatic slowdown in wireless traffic growth during the first half of 2012.</description></item><item><title>AT&amp;T effs users again</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/08/18/att-effs-users-again/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 12:41:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/08/18/att-effs-users-again/</guid><description>The beard, Jim Dalrymple nails it in AT&amp;amp;T fucks users… again:
“Our network sucks balls. If we tried to let all of you rapid iPhone users have FaceTime, our network would take a firey crash into Hell. Many of the executives that have been too goddamn cheap to upgrade the network are now scared shitless that they will lose their cushy bonuses. So we decided to fuck our users.”
Why? AT&amp;amp;T is only allowing cellular FaceTime if you buy into their new overpriced and underserviced family share plans.</description></item><item><title>No competition in Carrier space</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/08/06/no-competition-in-carrier-space/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 14:16:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/08/06/no-competition-in-carrier-space/</guid><description>If you are looking for more proof that there is no real competition in the US mobile carrier space, check out BGR’s iPhone: Data caps, upgrade fees blamed on iPhone by AT&amp;amp;T, Verizon by Brad Reed:
AT&amp;amp;T reported a 45% margin in Q2 2012 and Verizon reported a record-high 49% margin.
Challenge: Name one competitive industry with such high margins and such terrible service?</description></item><item><title>Two kinds of innovations in tech</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/07/19/two-kinds-of-innovations-in-tech/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 19:07:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/07/19/two-kinds-of-innovations-in-tech/</guid><description>Kevin Kelleher, writing for ReadWriteWeb in How AT&amp;amp;T &amp;amp; Verizon Learned to Stop Worrying and Love Data Hogs about AT&amp;amp;T&amp;rsquo;s new pricing model, nails the conclusion in regards to the carriers in the USA:
There are two kinds of innovations in tech. One that is often celebrated – the creation of great new things people will gladly pay for – and another that few companies will brag about – finding new ways to get people to pay for something they already have.</description></item><item><title>Carriers are the biggest threat to innovation</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/07/05/carriers-are-the-biggest-threat-to-innovation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 11:11:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/07/05/carriers-are-the-biggest-threat-to-innovation/</guid><description>Nilay Patel, writing for The Verge gets it in Five years after the iPhone, carriers are the biggest threat to innovation. Extremely clear and well written, too many awesome quotes.
Getting a device on a major carrier can take up to 15 months and cost millions of dollars; carriers are notorious for demanding custom devices in order to create customer lock-in. &amp;ldquo;Exclusivity is the bane of my existence,&amp;rdquo; says one source at a major phone manufacturer.</description></item><item><title>Adjusting the Cap</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/04/04/adjusting-the-cap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 19:39:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/04/04/adjusting-the-cap/</guid><description>Alex Knight, writing in his own blog Zero Distraction in The Disparity between Smartphones And Mobile Carriers sets the scene exactly as I see it:
There’s a massive disparity between data sucking smartphones and data plans offered by carriers. Customers know this, and the carriers are fully cognizant of it. The problem is they make a ton of money from you already, and since you probably don’t have a lot of choice as far as competition is concerned, they can charge whatever they see fit.</description></item><item><title>iPhone Data Plan Follies</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/02/25/iphone-data-plan-follies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 10:25:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/02/25/iphone-data-plan-follies/</guid><description>This week, three stories came to my attention regarding iPhone data plans and usage: man wins $850 from AT&amp;amp;T for data throttling, Siri is ruining your cellphone service, and its all about the camera.
iPhone user wins $850 in throttling case Source: Judge awards iPhone user $850 in throttling case
In short, so a guy who was sold the unlimited AT&amp;amp;T data plan gets throttled, sues AT&amp;amp;T in small claims court and wins some money.</description></item><item><title>The 4G deception</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/02/17/the-4g-deception/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2012 12:45:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/02/17/the-4g-deception/</guid><description>&lt;p>These days, all the US mobile carriers are touting their allegedly hot new 4G networks, pushing people to upgrade their phones and get up to 10x faster mobile data speeds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note the only single consumer benefit touted is a &lt;em>possibly&lt;/em> faster download time, it is not guaranteed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This whole thing is a deception. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>