<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Politics on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/tags/politics/</link><description>Recent content in Politics on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 10:06:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gun Control does Work</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/12/16/gun-control-does-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 10:06:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/12/16/gun-control-does-work/</guid><description>Personal note: I have lived in the USA for 9 years now, and think this place is magnificent. Two days ago, in Newtown CT, 20 children and 6 adults were massacred. The dark side of America that is in denial about gun violence, that refuses to even discuss gun control, that treats massacres as a normal and regular part of life, a country that gives up its civil rights over a single terrorist act, but takes no action on a score of massacres of its children, well, that just scares the shit out of me.</description></item><item><title>Lodsys still trolling</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/30/lodsys-still-trolling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 17:40:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/30/lodsys-still-trolling/</guid><description>Jacqui Cheng over at Ars Technica reminds us that iOS developers go into 2012 still battling patent troll Lodsys. Of course she interviewed Mike Lee:
&amp;ldquo;We analyzed the ubiquitous criminal nature of these companies,&amp;rdquo; Lee told Ars. &amp;ldquo;There is nothing you can do to prevent yourself from being targeted, regardless of platform, and regardless of how careful you are, because this is not patent infringement, it is simple extortion, and it is worldwide.</description></item><item><title>Bogus copyright claims under SOPA</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/30/bogus-copyright-claims-under-sopa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 17:32:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/30/bogus-copyright-claims-under-sopa/</guid><description>Mike Masnyck, writing in Techdirt asks a valid question: Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t There Be Significant Punishment For Bogus Copyright Claims That Kill Companies?
If enforcing their rights involves completely destroying someone else&amp;rsquo;s company, then, as Goldman notes, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be difficult?
Fighting a copyright claim costs at least 1 million dollars in legal fees, whether or not the claim is valid. Companies with deep pockets can and do use bogus claims to road-kill new competitors.</description></item><item><title>Not secret subpoena</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/30/not-secret-subpoena/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 17:23:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/30/not-secret-subpoena/</guid><description>Kudos to Twitter this week for not giving in and and responding to a Subpoena for user records without notifying the users in question. Twitter, according to their privacy policy, always notifies users when they can:
&amp;ldquo;However, to help users protect their rights, it is our policy to notify our users about law enforcement and governmental requests for their information, unless we are prevented by law from doing so.&amp;rdquo;
Matt Graves, Twitter</description></item><item><title>Is America Giving Up on the Future?</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/26/is-america-giving-up-on-the-future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 15:23:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/26/is-america-giving-up-on-the-future/</guid><description>Umair Haque, writing in the Harvard Business Review in Is America Giving Up on the Future? writes:
That the wealth of a nation isn&amp;rsquo;t merely the sum of its tradable riches; that a thriving marketplace isn&amp;rsquo;t a big box store; that industrial output matters less than human outcomes; that work that matters yields accomplishments that endure; that Goldman Sachs probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be as profitable as Apple, because builders should earn more than shufflers; that the worth of an enduring achievement is denominated in more than mere profit; that how we feel about our lives is worth more than how enviably glamorous they look; that tomorrow matters more — not less — than today.</description></item><item><title>The whole world is watching while the USA collapses</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/23/the-whole-world-is-watching-while-the-usa-collapses/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 11:14:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/23/the-whole-world-is-watching-while-the-usa-collapses/</guid><description>&lt;p>On Reddit a few days ago, &lt;em>spiderfarmer&lt;/em> put up a post entitled &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/nhb6f/the_whole_world_is_watching_while_the_usa/">The whole world is watching while the USA collapses&lt;/a>. I have reproduced it here in case it gets lost, but I thoroughly recommend you look through the comments thread. In short, based on the comments alone, he ain&amp;rsquo;t wrong.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The cartoon villain behind SOPA</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/23/the-cartoon-villain-behind-sopa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 10:59:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/23/the-cartoon-villain-behind-sopa/</guid><description>Kevin Fogarty, writing in Best idea of 2011: Give control of Internet content to group that sued a dead grandmother via IT World, goes after the backers of SOPA, especially the RIAA.
The anti-piracy enforcement arm of the RIAA has, for almost a decade, been so aggressive about investigating, suing and attempting to prosecute those it accused of illegally downloading movies or music that it was sued by illegal investigatory practices and invasion of privacy, for fraud, conspiracy and extortion, deceptive business practices and violation of the RICO statutes normally used to prosecute bosses of organized crime families.</description></item><item><title>Smoke Screening</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/21/smoke-screening/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 17:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/21/smoke-screening/</guid><description>Charles C Mann writing on Smoke Screening in Vanity Fair, spends an afternoon at the airport with Bruce Schneier looking at the TSA in action and asks whether any of it actually makes is safer? His conclusion is obviously no, locked cockpit doors and aware passengers are the only things that work. Even the $1.2b worth of scanners and another $1.2b in air marshals are totally useless.
We’re spending billions upon billions of dollars doing this—and it is almost entirely pointless.</description></item><item><title>Adam Savage on SOPA</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/21/adam-savage-on-sopa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 16:29:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/21/adam-savage-on-sopa/</guid><description>Adam Savage from Mythbusters writing in SOPA Could Destroy the Internet as We Know It at Popular Mechanics (sorry about their ads folks).
The Internet is probably the most important technological advancement of my lifetime. Its strength lies in its open architecture and its ability to allow a framework where all voices can be heard. Like the printing press before it (which states also tried to regulate, for centuries), it democratizes information, and thus it democratizes power.</description></item><item><title>Bring in the nerds</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/17/bring-in-the-nerds/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 12:06:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2011/12/17/bring-in-the-nerds/</guid><description>Joshua Kopstein, writing in Dear Congress, It&amp;rsquo;s No Longer OK To Not Know How The Internet Works, getting angry with Congress on the SOPA hearings:
It’d be one thing if legitimate technical questions directed at the bill’s supporters weren’t met with either silence or veiled accusations that the other side was sympathetic to piracy. Yet here we are with a group of elected officials openly supporting a bill they can’t explain, and having the temerity to suggest there’s no need to “bring in the nerds” to suss out what’s actually on it.</description></item></channel></rss>