<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Writing on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/tags/writing/</link><description>Recent content in Writing on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 15:32:14 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.com/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Where the Rights Are</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2022/10/26/where-the-rights-are/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 15:32:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2022/10/26/where-the-rights-are/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been writing software professionally for 32 years. I must have written several millions of lines of production code in that time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I do not own the rights to any of the work product I have made. It all belongs to someone else. That is the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The question is how can one go about making great software product, still earn a satisfactory living, and yet retain the rights on that work product and create a revenue steam off it?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Innocuous Birthday Career Advice</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2022/10/20/innocuous-birthday-career-advice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 12:38:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2022/10/20/innocuous-birthday-career-advice/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today, I turn 55. I now have over 32 years of work experience. These numbers got me thinking about what I wish I had known when I started my professional careers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve all heard this before. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s time to act on it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Go to Where the Puck Is Going</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2022/10/12/go-to-where-the-puck-is-going/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 13:57:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2022/10/12/go-to-where-the-puck-is-going/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Go to where the puck is going, not where it has been&amp;rdquo;. - Walter Gretzky (Wayne Gretzky&amp;rsquo;s father)
Should we be building new product on existing, proven software stacks, or taking the challenge to start using the newer tools? In this post, I take a high-level look at the technology landscape for commercial software development to aid in a thought exercise on how I would want to create new software products.</description></item><item><title>Optimizing Short Form Writing for Developers</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2022/08/22/optimizing-short-form-writing-for-developers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 12:20:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2022/08/22/optimizing-short-form-writing-for-developers/</guid><description>&lt;p>The vast majority of non-code writing performed by software engineers is &lt;strong>short form standard format&lt;/strong>, defined here as:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Short Form&lt;/strong>: A small amount of headings and text up to 1000 words&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Standard Format&lt;/strong>: The same standard structure or pattern of document repeated over and over again&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Yet even though its short form and standard format, it takes too much time and effort to produce these, so we developers conveniently &amp;ldquo;forget&amp;rdquo; to create these valuable documents (or mess up structure of them).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have found &lt;em>my&lt;/em> way to optimize the creation of these so I can spin them up quickly, deliver the information needed correctly, send them out and get back to coding.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What to write about next?</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2014/11/15/what-to-write-about-next/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2014 15:27:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2014/11/15/what-to-write-about-next/</guid><description>I was asked in a blog comment today how I decide what to write about. And once decided, how do I go about doing it. In this case, the answer was easy, I decided to try to answer the question. And deconstruct the process I go through as it happens.
Instructions: Read this post in black font first, then come back and look at the gray which deconstructs my thinking.</description></item><item><title>Horizons</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/06/06/horizons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 18:11:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/06/06/horizons/</guid><description>When I was a child, my horizon was the building I was in, my home. I could reach out and touch my family and whomever wandered into the house.
As a teenager, I got a bicycle, and my horizon was the neighborhoods within cycling range. I could reach out and touch my friends in nearby neighborhoods. And I felt less constrained.
Later, I learned to drive, and my horizon grew to the city I was living in.</description></item><item><title>My Mac Indie Writing Workflow</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/28/my-mac-indie-writing-workflow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 12:39:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/28/my-mac-indie-writing-workflow/</guid><description>Over the past few years, I have been writing more and more on my Mac, whether it be single blog posts, blog series, systems documentation, knowledge bases and other articles. The best part is that all the tools I use are indie developed from all over the world, are amazingly great and way better than their mainstream counterparts.
In this post, I want to share the tools I use to write and why I choose them.</description></item><item><title>Avoiding the Blogger Trap</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/08/avoiding-the-blogger-trap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 10:43:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/08/avoiding-the-blogger-trap/</guid><description>I totally agree with Marco in Avoiding the blogger trap:
People aren’t so one-sided. Everyone has a life that goes much deeper than the topics on their blogs.
and
This site represents me, and I’m random and eccentric and interested in a wide variety of subjects.
This site is me, with a hodge podge of posts ranging from opinion pieces, news, geeky ideas, advice, links, jokes, setups and productivity. I write what I find interesting.</description></item><item><title>Reading the Archives</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/07/reading-the-archives/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 09:20:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/07/reading-the-archives/</guid><description>Most people when they click on a link to a new blog, read the linked article and move on elsewhere. Google Analytics records this as a bounce - a visitor comes in, reads a single page and leaves.
One of my habits when I come across a new blog is to read the archives. Almost every blogging platform has archives and almost every blogger makes these available.
But why read the archives?</description></item><item><title>Email before the Open Web</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/30/email-before-the-open-web/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 09:09:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/30/email-before-the-open-web/</guid><description>Today, April 30, 2013 is the 20th anniversary of CERN making the WWW free, see Twenty Years of a free, open web. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share a story about how it was like before then.
The year was 1988 or 1989, and my Computer Science Professor wanted to send his first email. But first we had to connect our University to the fledgling Internet. Since I ran the UNIX lab, I was tasked to set this up.</description></item><item><title>Make Perfectly Good Mistakes</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/25/make-perfectly-good-mistakes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 15:31:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/25/make-perfectly-good-mistakes/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re not perfect, yet:
You can only learn from making perfectly good mistakes.
We all know of people&amp;rsquo;s reluctance to try things out in new software products because they are afraid of making mistakes and looking foolish. They are striving for perfect execution, yet unknowingly fail to learn the product or gain the benefits of its power.
Yet the failure to try new things is the biggest mistake of all. If you do not take a chance and try, you cannot learn anything.</description></item><item><title>Punctual</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/25/punctual/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 12:27:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/25/punctual/</guid><description>punc·tu·al /ˈpəNGkCHo͞oəl/
Adjective
Happening or doing something at the agreed or proper time; on time. Denoting or relating to an action that takes place at a particular point in time. Synonyms
precise - exact - accurate - prompt
One of my many peeves is with people who are not punctual. If we schedule a call or a meeting at a given time, I will be there, on time, prepared and ready to go.</description></item><item><title>Have to Have It Just to Have It</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/22/have-to-have-it-just-to-have-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 19:43:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/22/have-to-have-it-just-to-have-it/</guid><description>I often come across users who tell me they just have to have something in the software I am designing for them: some data or a report or an export. When I ask them how they use this requested item, or why they need it, they usually answer that they just have to have it. Sometimes, they even try to justify the request using the excuse that they have always had it, so they should continue to have it.</description></item><item><title>The people who love something are its best critics</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/19/the-people-who-love-something-are-its-best-critics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 13:39:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/19/the-people-who-love-something-are-its-best-critics/</guid><description>I have been accused of being an Apple fan-something as if this was a bad thing, a blinkered delusional existence, a sign of mental degradation. I could come back that it is a Stockholm Syndrome like relationship that binds Windows users to Excel, PowerPoint and Outlook. Or declare that Linux-on-the-desktop users are hallucinating when they claim productivity and usability in a sea of incomprehensibly complex, buggy and mediocre open source software.</description></item><item><title>Google Already Is Big Brother</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/09/google-already-is-big-brother/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 17:14:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/09/google-already-is-big-brother/</guid><description>You can, and probably already do, most of these without paying any money (in no particular order):
Use Google&amp;rsquo;s browser Chrome to visit web pages, which tell Google Analytics what you did Find information using Google Search, which tracks and saves your searches, search attempts and selections; with the results customized by Google&amp;rsquo;s model of you Jump to your favorite sites using a Google Toolbar extension or built-in search that checks each site you visit Send and receive all your personal email via Gmail (and probably work emails too), analyzed and filtered by Postini Find out whats going on (and should be going on) in your life and around you using Google Now Chat with others on Google Talk Schedule your life in Google Calendar Maintain your relationships and connections in Google Contacts Socialize via Google+ and participate in Google Groups Use Google Maps for locating yourself and getting around Check in with Google Latitude Use a Google phone (Android) for mobile calls, using a Motorola or Nexus handset Call internationally using Google Voice Read the news via Google News and get your feeds via Feedburner Watch TV and other Video on YouTube Read books from Google Books Listen to tunes from Google Play Find a restaurant using Zagat Plan you next vacation on Frommers Log in to other services using your Google ID and OAuth Save and share your personal photos on Picasa Purchase stuff via Google Shopper using Google Wallet Save your files on Google Drive Track your shares and investments on Google Finance Click on ads served by Google, DoubleClick, AdMob, AdMeld, Teracent, and AdScape Create, edit and collaborate using Google Apps Write your blog on Blogger Save your code on Google code Access the internet over Google fiber (OK, so this costs some money) And then there&amp;rsquo;s bookmarks, offers, iGoogle, translation, alerts and scholar.</description></item><item><title>Is this the end?</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/08/is-this-the-end/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 12:32:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/08/is-this-the-end/</guid><description>The indie business is cyclical, a sin wave of quiet and busy times. The peaks are high and the troughs are low.
When an indie is busy, there is nothing better, no higher high. They are working with great clients, creating amazing products, solving the unsolvable, slaying dragons and earning enough money to pay the bills.
But when an indie is quiet, there is nothing worse, no lower low. No clients to please, no products to create, no problems to solve, no dragons to slay and no income coming in.</description></item><item><title>Go Home</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/04/go-home/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/04/04/go-home/</guid><description>I was talking with a friend the other night about their number one concern with their new job, in that they expect to have to work until 11PM every night and would therefore give up yoga, movies and dating. I almost dropped my drink (which is a horrifying thought for an Aussie).
WTF! NO! Go Home! You work to live, not live to work.
I was that person, the one who worked all hours.</description></item><item><title>Oldest Trace of You on the Internet</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/26/oldest-trace-of-you-on-the-internet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 10:20:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/26/oldest-trace-of-you-on-the-internet/</guid><description>For a lark, and in response to this tweet:
what's the oldest trace of yourself you can find on the internet?
&amp;mdash; Kyle McDonald (@kcimc) March 24, 2013 I started on the Internet in the late 1980&amp;rsquo;s when it was still called Arpanet. I connected our University of Cape Town UNIX boxes via UUCP to Rhodes University in South Africa which in turn used UUCP to talk to Oxford University in the UK, which in turn connected to one of the Ivy Leagues in the USA.</description></item><item><title>Modular Mac Pros, the new Burroughs B20?</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/09/modular-mac-pros/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 15:06:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/09/modular-mac-pros/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching a conversation on APP.NET speculating about the next Mac Pro form factor, triggered by Dan Frakes&amp;rsquo;s article The time is (finally) right for a Mac minitower in MacWorld. All we know about it is that Tim Cook said they were coming.
One of the speculative themes in the discussion is a &amp;ldquo;modular&amp;rdquo; Mac Pro, where adding CPU&amp;rsquo;s, drives or expansion cards would be a simple case of stacking another module on and using [thunderbolt](http://en.</description></item></channel></rss>