<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Macintosh on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/tags/macintosh/</link><description>Recent content in Macintosh on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 11:17:10 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.com/tags/macintosh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Increasing File Descriptor Ulimit on MacOS</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2023/01/01/increasing-file-descriptor-ulimit-on-macos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 11:17:10 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2023/01/01/increasing-file-descriptor-ulimit-on-macos/</guid><description>Warning: This post is only for developers who are having issues when coding against file descriptors in the form of C-style file handles or sockets on MacOS. For everyone else, this does not apply.
Running out of Resources Right now I am developing an application that uses sockets (underneath a stack of other software) for inter-process communication. The problem is that after a few debug runs or crashes (I did say developing), the application will not start again from resource starvation.</description></item><item><title>Two Months with the M1 Macbook Pro</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2022/11/03/two-months-with-the-m1-macbook-pro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 12:01:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2022/11/03/two-months-with-the-m1-macbook-pro/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is my fourth CPU Architecture transition in the Apple ecosystem, from the Motorolas on the II&amp;rsquo;s and LC, through the PowerPCs in the Titanium Powerbook, Intels on the Aluminum MacBooks to the ARM M1 today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>This&lt;/em> transition has been the smoothest by far, so much so, it&amp;rsquo;s not worth posting about. But that would overlook the incredible amount of work performed by untold thousands of people in building and testing their software to ensure this invisible transition happened.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it would overlook the significant changes in hardware too, not just the CPU architecture, but also the move to new GPUs, screens, security chips, ports and keyboard.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Homebrew Happiness</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/09/29/homebrew-happiness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 12:12:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/09/29/homebrew-happiness/</guid><description>If you are expecting an article about beer, this is not it. This is about the best product that helps install and manage the Open Source software on the Macintosh computer that Apple decided not to include in OS X.
In short, I use a lot of Open Source products for work, like postgresql, redis, mongo, node, boost libraries and rbenv. Installing and managing them natively on a Mac was a pain.</description></item><item><title>Fast SSH Windows with iTerm 2</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/07/18/fast-ssh-windows-with-iterm-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 22:14:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/07/18/fast-ssh-windows-with-iterm-2/</guid><description>I have a bunch of Linux boxes that I need to access via SSH, whether to install things, start or stop processes or browse log files.
But it is a pain to have to launch a new terminal window and type in the whole SSH command line:
$ ssh hiltmon@servername.domainname.local Yep, I am that lazy. Or really, I do this so often I needed a faster way to do this.</description></item><item><title>My Mac Indie Writing Workflow</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/28/my-mac-indie-writing-workflow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 12:39:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/05/28/my-mac-indie-writing-workflow/</guid><description>Over the past few years, I have been writing more and more on my Mac, whether it be single blog posts, blog series, systems documentation, knowledge bases and other articles. The best part is that all the tools I use are indie developed from all over the world, are amazingly great and way better than their mainstream counterparts.
In this post, I want to share the tools I use to write and why I choose them.</description></item><item><title>Make iTerm 2 more Mac-like</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/13/make-iterm-2-more-mac-like/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 12:08:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/02/13/make-iterm-2-more-mac-like/</guid><description>I just switched from using Apple’s built-in Terminal.app to the free iTerm 2 on a recommendation from Brett Terpstra. I’m already loving the hot-key profiles to launch uniquely colored remote sessions, the split panes, and the brilliant hotkey window (useful to run a single command and get rid of it).
But there are a few things that needed some work. Some of the usual Mac editing keys did not work, I got rid of a few annoyances and added a few lovely preferences, and I needed the ability to create a new terminal window on the current space as part of my being productive with virtual desktops flow (Just like Browser Windows on All Desktops).</description></item><item><title>BBEdit still Rules</title><link>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/10/10/bbedit-still-rules/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 09:48:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.com/blog/2012/10/10/bbedit-still-rules/</guid><description>Lovely article on how the stalwart classic BBEdit still rules by Andy Ihnatko (@ihnatko) on Macworld today, entitled Mac classics: Why BBEdit rules
“BBEdit’s still important because at its essential core, it’s a tool for working with text,” says Rich Siegel, Bare Bones Software’s founder and CEO. “Not text for presentation, as in a word processor or page-layout application, but rather text as data supplied to other software: code for compilers and interpreters, markup and Web applications for Web browsers, log files and data tables for analysis, and for any tool that inhales raw text and turns it into something else.</description></item></channel></rss>