<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Slogger on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/slogger/</link><description>Recent content in Slogger on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 10:43:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/slogger/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Slogger after 6 Months</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/04/23/slogger-after-6-months/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 10:43:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/04/23/slogger-after-6-months/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been using &lt;a href="http://brettterpstra.com">Brett Terpstra&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> (&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/ttscoff">@ttscoff&lt;/a>) &lt;a href="http://brettterpstra.com/projects/slogger/">Slogger&lt;/a> for the last six months, and I think it&amp;rsquo;s time to review it. Slogger is a script and a set of plugins that log your online activity each day into &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/day-one/id422304217?mt=12&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=10l894">Day One&lt;/a>, the best journaling application for OS X, or in Markdown files if you prefer. It&amp;rsquo;s a core part of my &lt;a href="https://hiltmon.com/blog/2013/03/14/backup-your-online-life/">Backing up your Online Life&lt;/a> process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>TL;DR: It&amp;rsquo;s totally worth taking the time to set it up and get it going. The data captured is so useful and often hard to gain access to, especially as we operate across many services, and as these services come and go.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Backup Your Online Life</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/03/14/backup-your-online-life/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 14:15:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/03/14/backup-your-online-life/</guid><description>The big tech news today is that Google is shutting down its Reader RSS Sync service, and my Twitter and App.Net feeds are full of people upset about it.
I&amp;rsquo;m not because I planned for it. Free web service shutdowns have happened before and free web service shutdowns will happen again (with apologies to Pythia). So I regularly backup my online life. (Links to do so are below.)
By now, we&amp;rsquo;ve all been on the Internet long enough to know that everything changes, frequently.</description></item><item><title>Be Organized and Productive</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/12/26/be-organized-and-productive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2012 16:59:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/12/26/be-organized-and-productive/</guid><description>The theme of 2012 was all about getting organized and productive using software. I may have spent 2012 developing Kifu and some internal applications for clients, but I spent a lot of time this year getting better organized and more productive on my Mac. It’s ridiculous how much this has paid off.
So, instead of a cool-products-of-2012-year-in-review post, here are many of the things I do and tools I use to be organized and productive, with thanks to those to shared the ideas with us.</description></item><item><title>Yahoo Finance Logger for Slogger</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/12/01/yahoo-finance-logger-for-slogger/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 16:24:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/12/01/yahoo-finance-logger-for-slogger/</guid><description>One thing I find myself doing every once in a while is trying to find out the $AAPL share price for a given date. This usually requires a trip to Google Finance or Yahoo Finance and a need to download a data table to find what I need.
Wouldn’t it be nice if this information was in my journal?
So I spun up a simple Slogger plugin to do it. This plugin:</description></item><item><title>Day One iCloud Sync Fail</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/11/17/day-one-icloud-sync-fail/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 14:08:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/11/17/day-one-icloud-sync-fail/</guid><description>This post seems to have become popular. To clarify, the problem is with iCloud, Day One is just plain brilliant and you should all be using it.
I use the Day One journalling program a lot, especially to log commits and all social activity using Slogger. But today I noticed that the Journals on all my devices were out of sync, and new entries created were not passed on to other devices.</description></item><item><title>Google Analytics Logger for Slogger</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/11/14/google-analytics-logger-for-slogger/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 09:14:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/11/14/google-analytics-logger-for-slogger/</guid><description>This article explains how to set up Brett Terpstra&amp;rsquo;s Slogger with a new plugin to journal your daily Google Analytics site stats. This plugin supports:
Multiple web properties as long as they are under the same Google login. Multiple dates so you can skip a few Slogger run days and catch up (or back fill). Only logs a full day&amp;rsquo;s worth of stats, so if it runs now, it logs up to yesterday&amp;rsquo;s stats.</description></item><item><title>Too Many Menu Bar Apps?</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/10/16/too-many-menu-bar-apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 17:27:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/10/16/too-many-menu-bar-apps/</guid><description>These days, in order to maximize my productivity, I seem to be running a lot of menu bar apps on my Macintosh OS X system. So many that I had to buy a menu bar manager, Bartender! Add what you use in the comments.
Here’s what each one is and why I use it (in no particular order):
1Password - One of my must have tools, enables me to reach and log into sites securely using strong site-specific passwords.</description></item></channel></rss>