<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scrivener on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/scrivener/</link><description>Recent content in Scrivener on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 17:37:51 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/scrivener/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One-Key Format Presets in Scrivener</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2015/03/07/one-key-format-presets-in-scrivener/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 17:37:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2015/03/07/one-key-format-presets-in-scrivener/</guid><description>I am writing a lot of business documents in Scrivener, and even though it&amp;rsquo;s the wrong way to do it, I use Scrivener&amp;rsquo;s format presets (think paragraph styles) to quickly format headings, bulleted lists and paragraphs in each sub-document. This way I minimize post-processing (and the business format is intentionally boring so I do not need any fancy layouts).
But it&amp;rsquo;s a hassle to have to take my hands off the keyboard to click through the Format / Apply Formatting / Apply Preset menu tree or hit the tiny format preset dropdown ¶a to set the current paragraph style.</description></item><item><title>Melding Scrivener and Marked</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2014/05/05/melding-scrivener-and-marked/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 20:07:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2014/05/05/melding-scrivener-and-marked/</guid><description>If you are a regular reader of this blog, you will know that I do all my writing using Markdown format, short-form in Byword, long-form in Scrivener and generate the final document using Marked.
In short: I write all my work documents, including letters, reports and software documentation in Markdown formatted text files and then format them using Marked and a standard stylesheet (See Letterhead - Markdown Style for how that works).</description></item><item><title>The Markdown Payoff</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2014/04/27/the-markdown-payoff/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2014 12:33:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2014/04/27/the-markdown-payoff/</guid><description>A long, long time ago in a galaxy far, far away, I switched to Markdown format for documents, notes and other scratchings. (And wrote about it - see the posts in the Markdown category).
Was switching to Markdown a good call? Did it pay off? And if so, how?
I actually wrote this post not knowing how it would turn out. I wanted to know for myself if it paid off, or if I just followed a fad.</description></item><item><title>Why Microsoft Word must Die</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/10/13/why-microsoft-word-must-die/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 09:57:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/10/13/why-microsoft-word-must-die/</guid><description>Charles Stross, yes, that Charles Stross writes in Why Microsoft Word must Die:
The .doc file format was also obfuscated, deliberately or intentionally: rather than a parseable document containing formatting and macro metadata, it was effectively a dump of the in-memory data structures used by word, with pointers to the subroutines that provided formatting or macro support.
He focuses on the usability issues, the compatibility issues, the inconstancies and the forced need to upgrade just to read other people&amp;rsquo;s documents - and the idiocy of using this incomprehensible, short lived format in publishing.</description></item><item><title>My Mac Indie Writing Workflow</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/05/28/my-mac-indie-writing-workflow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 12:39:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/05/28/my-mac-indie-writing-workflow/</guid><description>Over the past few years, I have been writing more and more on my Mac, whether it be single blog posts, blog series, systems documentation, knowledge bases and other articles. The best part is that all the tools I use are indie developed from all over the world, are amazingly great and way better than their mainstream counterparts.
In this post, I want to share the tools I use to write and why I choose them.</description></item><item><title>Rarely Microsoft Office</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/11/07/rarely-microsoft-office/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 12:03:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/11/07/rarely-microsoft-office/</guid><description>I rarely use Microsoft Office. There, I said it. And it&amp;rsquo;s true. There are electronic cobwebs on my copy. You may now run out of the room screaming.
For many, this is like saying I rarely bathe. I rarely use Microsoft Office because I have absolutely no reason to use it except for two specific cases.
Email, not Outlook There are several reasons why I don&amp;rsquo;t use Outlook for email:</description></item></channel></rss>