<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Email on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/email/</link><description>Recent content in Email on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 09:09:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/email/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Email before the Open Web</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/04/30/email-before-the-open-web/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 09:09:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/04/30/email-before-the-open-web/</guid><description>Today, April 30, 2013 is the 20th anniversary of CERN making the WWW free, see Twenty Years of a free, open web. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share a story about how it was like before then.
The year was 1988 or 1989, and my Computer Science Professor wanted to send his first email. But first we had to connect our University to the fledgling Internet. Since I ran the UNIX lab, I was tasked to set this up.</description></item><item><title>Inbox Kinda Zero</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/12/01/inbox-kinda-zero/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 14:02:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/12/01/inbox-kinda-zero/</guid><description>The idea behind Inbox Zero is to manage email overload. Basically, you aggressively process your email inbox by
Deleting everything you don’t need, want, care about, don’t care about, couldn’t be bothered with or is too old to act on. Respond and file what you can process quickly. Queue, by filing, emails that you need to get back to. Schedule tasks and time to process the queue folder. With Inbox Zero, if there is an email in the inbox, it needs to be processed away.</description></item><item><title>Reducing Inboxes</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/11/06/reducing-inboxes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 11:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/11/06/reducing-inboxes/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve all heard about Inbox Zero, where you try to reclaim your email, your attention and your life by clearing out your email inbox. I needed to reduce the number of inboxes first.
Those of us who have been on the Internet for decades have amassed a large number of email addresses on a variety of services. As time passed, and new services emerged, we added more. Most of us are loathe to close any of these addresses down just in case we get an email there.</description></item><item><title>Email Etiquette</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/10/24/email-etiquette/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 15:38:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/10/24/email-etiquette/</guid><description>&lt;p>I don’t know about you, but I get a lot of emails across a lot of accounts and the time and effort to process my inbox is growing exponentially. I just wish that senders and responders on email would follow some basic etiquette rules that will make our use of email both more pleasant and more productive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Email is a form of communication which is a reflection of you. Bad email etiquette reflects badly on you, and a record of this is kept in mailboxes over which you have no control. Good email etiquette reflects well on you, improves your public perception and persona and increases the chance of a prompt and comprehensive response. It’s not hard to maintain good email etiquette once you know what it is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing before we start, before creating or responding to an email, ask yourself this: is email the right medium for this communication? If you are not sure, pick up the phone or wander over to the person and have a conversation. Email only if it is the right medium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And always follow good etiquette. This article contains a comprehensive list of rules and recommendations learned through experience and research.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>