<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reviews on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/reviews/</link><description>Recent content in Reviews on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 21:09:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pinbrowser for Pinboard Updated</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/06/19/pinbrowser-updated/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 21:09:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/06/19/pinbrowser-updated/</guid><description>I just downloaded the updated Pinbrowser for Pinboard from the App Store, an iOS app by Mikael Konutgan (@mkonutgan), and it just got a whole lot better.
Pinboard is a paid for bookmarking site that focuses on speed, utility and longevity (and anti-socialness!). Pinbrowser is an iPhone and iPad application to access your Pinboard, other&amp;rsquo;s bookmarks (making it more social) and the all famous popular bookmarks list.
It&amp;rsquo;s the social aspect that attracted me to the product in the first place.</description></item><item><title>Fix the Mac Function Keys with Palua</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/05/01/fix-the-mac-function-keys-with-palua/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 13:04:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/05/01/fix-the-mac-function-keys-with-palua/</guid><description>By default, the function keys on Apple keyboards are mapped to the Apple functions on them, like brightness, volume and Mission Control. To access them as F1 - F12 requires you to hit the fn key as well. You could always reverse this in Preferences / Keyboard by checking Use all F1, F2, etc. keys as standard function keys.
But this change is system-wide. What if you want the default Apple behavior most of the time, but Function key behavior in certain applications, for example, in virtual machines?</description></item><item><title>Glui - a better Skitch</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/02/20/glui-a-better-skitch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 19:09:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2013/02/20/glui-a-better-skitch/</guid><description>Ever since Evernote purchased and then ruined Skitch (See my Bye bye Skitch, Hello LittleSnapper post), I’ve been looking for a replacement product. A lightweight snap, annotate and save to PNG or share the image app. And I think Glui may be it.
I just wanted an app that just does the following like the original Skitch betas:
Snap Quick Annotate Save as image, or Share the image Go away Glui, by Sebastian Razola (@razola), does exactly that.</description></item><item><title>Windows 8 Preview on a Tablet</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/09/27/windows-8-preview-on-a-tablet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 17:33:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/09/27/windows-8-preview-on-a-tablet/</guid><description>While on holiday, I got to play with the Windows 8 Preview on a Samsung tablet. It made some notes of the experience, then decided to wait until I returned home to see what I remembered about the experience.
The tablet itself was larger than the iPad, a lot thicker, a lot heavier and had a lot more ports. It also came with a stylus and a keyboard dock which was useful in turning it into a laptop when needed.</description></item><item><title>Bye bye Skitch, Hello LittleSnapper</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/09/27/bye-bye-skitch/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 15:29:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/09/27/bye-bye-skitch/</guid><description>Editor&amp;rsquo;s Note: Written six months ago, I&amp;rsquo;ve since moved on to using Glui - a better Skitch to replace Skitch.
Bye bye Skitch I’ve been using Skitch to grab screenshots since the first beta was announced way back in June, 2007. I paid for Skitch Plus in February 2011 because I loved the product, and the work by Plasq, so much. Then Evernote purchased Skitch and I hoped that they would not mess it up.</description></item><item><title>Slicy Photoshop Artwork</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/07/11/slicy-photoshop-artwork/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 21:50:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/07/11/slicy-photoshop-artwork/</guid><description>I have been using the same process to export application artwork using Adobe Photoshop forever. Most Mac, iOS and Web applications have large numbers of small image files that are used everywhere. They need to be sliced up, scaled and exported into the files and formats needed by the application. Exporting multiple art items in multiple resolutions has been a tedious and time consuming task, a task that had to be repeated manually every time the artwork changed.</description></item><item><title>The Demo Bag</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/06/05/the-demo-bag/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 12:31:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/06/05/the-demo-bag/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m demonstrating software this afternoon, so out comes the demo bag. It&amp;rsquo;s a Cocoon 15&amp;quot; GRID-IT™ Case (not an affiliate link) that I picked up at the local Apple store.
The things that sold it to me are:
It&amp;rsquo;s black and conservative looking so no-one knows how cool it is It&amp;rsquo;s a hard-ish case, so my goods are protected It&amp;rsquo;s the right size for a 15&amp;quot; Macbook Pro, an iPad and related cables, and no bulkier But the biggest selling point of all, it has the GRID-IT™ system, no more digging around a bag to find the cables and accessories needed in a demo.</description></item><item><title>Marked 1.4</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/04/09/marked-1-dot-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 12:13:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/04/09/marked-1-dot-4/</guid><description>If you are a fans of the The Markdown Mindset, then the must-have Markdown preview app Marked has just been updated to V1.4 by Brett Terpstra.
Marked has gone from a simple preview app that always sits to the right of my writing window to an integral part of my writing, checking, publishing and delivery process. As you know, I already do all my writing in Markdown. I use Marked to preview the results using the formatting I intend to deliver it (Kifu format, blog format, report format), and then use it&amp;rsquo;s great export features to generate the HTML or PDFs I send out.</description></item></channel></rss>