<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>iPad on Hiltmon</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/ipad/</link><description>Recent content in iPad on Hiltmon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2012 13:47:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hiltmon.github.io/tags/ipad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2012 Year End iPad Essentials</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/12/26/2012-year-end-ipad-essentials/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2012 13:47:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/12/26/2012-year-end-ipad-essentials/</guid><description>I posted my 2012 iPad Essentials (excluding games) in March this year when the iPad 3 came out. Since then, the iPad 4 and the iPad mini have launched. Surprisingly enough, the early 2012 essentials (excluding games) have changed very little:
New Additions The Magazine - Technically not an app, The Magazine is a brilliant new take on how a magazine should work, with great writing on a wide variety of interesting topics.</description></item><item><title>iPad 4G Misleading</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/03/27/ipad-4g-misleading/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 10:08:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/03/27/ipad-4g-misleading/</guid><description>As reported in the Verge, Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPad &amp;lsquo;4G&amp;rsquo; advertising labeled misleading by Australian watchdog, may be banned. The same can be said for the fictitious 4G on my iPhone 4S.
As a proud Aussie, I am a fan of the ACCC (Australian Competition and Consumer Commission) and Australia&amp;rsquo;s Trade Practices Act that supports them. In short, companies cannot lie or mislead customers in any way, or the ACCC can nail them and force them to make things right.</description></item><item><title>2012 iPad Essentials</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/03/17/2012-ipad-essentials/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 13:30:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/03/17/2012-ipad-essentials/</guid><description>Editor’s Note: This was written way back in March 2012 with the launch of the iPad 3. For updates see 2012 Year End iPad Essentials.
The new iPad arrived yesterday. Instead of restoring from a backup, I decided to build it clean and install only essential apps. Here are the ones (excluding games) that made it in the first 24 hours, pretty much in order of addition:
iBooks - I read a lot of ePub books on the iPad, and the new retina text rendering is so great.</description></item><item><title>First impressions of the new iPad</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/03/16/first-impressions-of-the-new-ipad/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 14:19:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/03/16/first-impressions-of-the-new-ipad/</guid><description>In short, between the iPad 2 and the new iPad (retina):
Weight: Same Thickness: Same Screen: Yowser! The old screen looks pixellated and blurry, the new screen is brilliant. Also a lot warmer. Performance: Same Between the original and the new iPad (retina):
Weight: Oh, so much lighter Thickness: Oh, so much thinner Screen: As above, but the original was warmer than the iPad 2. Performance: Blazingly faster, yet the original is still no slouch.</description></item><item><title>Writing on the iPad</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/03/09/writing-on-the-ipad/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2012 11:12:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/03/09/writing-on-the-ipad/</guid><description>This comment by JohnDoey (reproduced in full without permission) on the Asymco article The new feeds and speeds: iPad vs. MacBook Air and iMac sums up the iPad writing experience beautifully (although I think the iPad is a good production system too):
I&amp;rsquo;m a writer also. You missed a key point about writing on iPad.
Writers who are using iPads are not using them like Macs (or Mac clones,) they are using them like typewriters.</description></item><item><title>iPad - On Two Years of Use</title><link>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/03/09/ipad-on-two-years-of-use/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2012 09:44:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://hiltmon.github.io/blog/2012/03/09/ipad-on-two-years-of-use/</guid><description>Can you believe it, the iPad has been around only two years, two! Yet it feels like there was never a time before we had them.
I was one of those who pre-ordered the original iPad on launch (and the iPad 2 on its launch). I also wrote three blog posts back then, and it seems my usage patterns have not changed that much:
Apr 4, 2010 iPad First Impressions - written after 24 hours of use Apr 12,2010 It&amp;rsquo;s Been One Week Since You Looked at Me - after 1 week of use May 15, 2010 iPad Update - After Almost a Month Traveling With It - in Eastern Europe as my only computing device.</description></item></channel></rss>